Ah. My son's loyal wife returns
unkilled by the heathen.
- So he accepted our bribe?
- No. He did not.
Then why does he stay?
My scouts tell me that he has not advanced.
He waits for you at York.
He says he will attack no more towns
if you are man enough to come and face him.
Did he?
The Welsh bowmen will not be detected
arriving so far around his flank.
The main force of our armies
from France land here
to the north of Edinburgh.
Conscripts from Ireland
will approach from the southwest...
to here.
Welsh bowmen, troops from France,
Irish conscripts.
But they'd take weeks to assemble.
I dispatched them... before I sent your wife.
So our little ruse succeeded. Thank you.
And while this upstart
awaits my arrival in York,
my forces will have arrived
in Edinburgh, behind him.
You spoke with this...
Wallace in private?
Tell me...
What kind of man is he?
A mindless barbarian.
Not a king like you, my Lord.
You may return to your embroidery.
Humbly, my Lord.
You brought back the money?
No. I gave it to ease the suffering
of the children of this war.
That's what happens
when you send a woman.
Forgive me, sire.
I thought that generosity might demonstrate
your greatness to those you mean to rule.
My greatness
will be better demonstrated
when Wallace returns to Scotland
and finds his country in ashes.
William.
There's riders approaching.
A personal escort of the Princess.
Aye.
Must have made an impression.
- Aye.
- I didn't think you were in the tent that long.
It's true. The English ships
are coming from the South.
I don't know about the Welsh yet,
but the Irish have landed.
- I had to see it myself to believe it.
- Why are the Irish fighting with the English?
I wouldn't worry about them.
Didn't I tell you before?
It's my island.
Hamish, ride ahead to Edinburgh
and assemble the council. Order it.
Right. Come on.
- Your island?
- My island. Yup.
- We'll have to negotiate.
- Please, gentlemen.
Lords, Craig is right.
This time our only option is to negotiate.
Unless you want to see Edinburgh razed...
My army has marched for many days.
And we still have preparations to make,
so I'll make this plain.
We require every soldier you can summon,
your personal escorts, even yourselves.
And we need them now.
With such a force arrayed against us,
it's time to discuss other options.
Other options?
Don't you wish at least
to lead your men onto the field
and barter a better deal with Longshanks
- before you run?
- Sir William...
- We cannot defeat them.
- We can.
- Sir William.
- And we will.
We won at Stirling, and still you quibble.
We won at York
and you would not support us.
If you'll no stand up with us now,
I'd say you're cowards.
If you are Scotsmen,
I'm ashamed to call myself one.
Please, Sir William, speak with me alone.
I beg you.
You've achieved so much,
but fighting these odds,
it looks like rage, not courage.
It's well beyond rage.
Help me.
In the name of Christ, help yourselves.
Now is our chance. Now.
If we join, we can win. If we win,
we'll have what none of us
have ever had before.
A country of our own.
You're the rightful leader
and there is strength in you, I see it.
Unite us.
Unite us. Unite the clans.
- All right.
- Right.
This cannot be the way.
You said yourself
the nobles will not support Wallace.
So how does it help us
to join the side that is slaughtered?
I gave him my word.
I know it is hard. Being a leader is.
My son...
Son...
Look at me.
I cannot be King.
You and you alone can rule Scotland.
What I tell you, you must do.
Not for me, not for yourself,
but for your country.
Right, lads, make way. Coming through.
Make way, lads.
- The Bruce is not coming, William.
- He'll come.
Mornay and Lochlan have come.
So will the Bruce.
Quite a lovely... gathering.
Wouldn't you agree?
- The archers are ready, sire.
- Not the archers.
My scouts say their archers
are miles away and no threat.
Arrows cost money.
Use up the Irish. The dead cost nothing.
And send in the infantry and cavalry.
Infantry.
Cavalry.
Advance.
Ah, good to see ye this morning.
Irish!
Glad to have ye with us. Watch this.
Mornay? Lochlan?
I gave Mornay
double his lands in Scotland
and matching estates in England.
Lochlan turned... for much less.
Archers.
I beg your pardon, sire?
Won't we hit our own troops?
Yes.
But we'll hit theirs as well. We have reserves.
Attack.
Archers.
Send in our reinforcements.
Send in the rest.
Bring me Wallace. Alive, if possible.
Dead... just as good.
Send us news of our victory. Shall we retire?
Protect the King.
Get up.
- Get him out of here.
- Jesus.
Go.
I'm dying.
Let me be.
No.
You're going to live.
I've lived long enough to live free.
Proud...
to see you become the man you are.
I'm a happy man.
I'm the one who's rotting.
But I think your face looks graver than mine.
Son...
We must have alliance
with England to prevail here.
You achieved that.
You saved your family
and increased your land.
In time, you will have
all the power in Scotland.
Lands.
Titles. Men.
Power. Nothing.
- Nothing?
- I have nothing.
Men fight for me because if they do not
I throw them off my land
and I starve their wives and their children.
Those men
who bled the ground red at Falkirk...
They fought for William Wallace, and he
fights for something that I've never had.
And I took it from him when I betrayed him
and I saw it in his face on the battlefield.
And it's tearing me apart.
Well, all men betray. All lose heart.
I don't want to lose heart.
I want to believe...
as he does.
I will never be on the wrong side again.
No.
Lord Craig, is it true about Mornay?
Aye. Wallace rode into his bedchamber
and killed him.
More of a liability now than ever he was.
And there's no telling who'll be next.
Maybe you.
Maybe me.
It doesn't matter.
- I'm serious, Robert.
- So am I.
Christ. Shit.
Search the place.
Lochlan.
William Wallace killed 50 men.
50 if it was one.
100 men... with his own sword.
Cut through them like...
Moses through the Red Sea.
His legend grows.
It will be worse than before.
He rallies new volunteers in every Scottish
town. When he replenishes his numbers...
They're sheep. Mere sheep.
Easily dispersed if we strike the shepherd.
Very well.
Pick a flock of your finest assassins
and set a meeting.
My Lord, Wallace is renowned
for his ability to smell an ambush.
If what Lord Hamilton tells me is correct
he warmed to our future Queen
and would trust her.
So we'll dispatch her
with the notion that she comes in peace.
My Lord,
the Princess might be taken hostage
or her life be put in jeopardy.
My son would be most distressed by that.
But in truth if she were to be killed,
we would soon find the King of France
a useful ally against the Scots.
You see...
As King, you must find
the good in any situation.
It's William Wallace, sure.
And he's given up his sword. Be ready.
My Lady.
I received your message.
This is... the second time
you've warned me of danger.
Why?
There will be a new shipment
of supplies coming north next month.
Foods and weapons. They will...
No, stop.
Why do you help me?
Because of the way
you are looking at me now.
Just when we thought all hope was lost,
our noble saviors have arrived.
Off with their hoods.
Sir William, we come to seek a meeting.
Well, what's the point?
- You've all sworn loyalty to Longshanks.
- An oath to a liar is no oath at all.
Every man of us is ready
to swear loyalty to you.
So let the council swear publicly.
We cannot.
Some scarcely believe you're alive.
Others think you'll pay them Mornay's wages.
So we bid you to Edinburgh.
Meet us two days from now. Pledge us
your pardon and we'll unite behind you.
- Scotland will be one.
- One?
- You mean us and you.
- No.
I mean this.
It's the pledge of Robert the Bruce.
You do know it's a trap. Tell him.
If the Bruce wanted to kill you,
he'd have done it at Falkirk.
Aye.
I know. I saw.
All right, leaving him aside,
what about the others?
Scheming bastards who couldn't agree on
the color of shite. It's a trap. Are you blind?
Look at us.
We've got to try. We can't do this alone.
Joining the nobles is our only hope.
You know what happens if we don't?
What?
Nothing.
- I don't want to be a martyr.
- Nor I.
I want to live.
I want a home, and children. And peace.
- Do ye?
- Aye, I do.
I've asked God for those things.
It's all for nothing if you don't have freedom.
- It's just a dream, William.
- A dream? Just a...
Well, then,
what have we been doing all this time?
We've lived that dream.
Your dream isn't about freedom.
It's about Murron.
You're doing this to be a hero
because you think she sees ye.
I don't think she sees me. I know she does.
And your father sees you, too.
Jesus.
Shall I come with you?
No. I'll go alone.
- I'll see you after.
- Right.
Sooner rather than later, I hope.
- He won't come.
- He will.
I know he will.
My Lord. He approaches.
No!
Stay out of it, Robert.
Get away.
The Bruce is not to be harmed,
that's the arrangement.
Father!
You rotting bastard!
Why?
Longshanks required Wallace.
So did our nobles.
That was the price of your crown.
Die.
I want you to die.
Soon enough I'll be dead.
- And you'll be King.
- I don't want anything from you.
You're not a man.
And you're not my father.
You're my son
and you have always known my mind.
- You deceived me.
- You let yourself be deceived.
In your heart, you always knew
what had to happen here.
At last, you know what it means to hate.
Now you're ready to be a king.
My hate...
will die with you.
William Wallace,
you stand in taint of high treason.
- Against whom?
- Against your King.
Have you anything to say?
Never in my whole life
did I swear allegiance to him.
It matters not. He is your King.
Confess and you may receive a quick death.
Deny and you must be purified by pain.
Do you confess?
Then on the morrow
you shall receive your purification.
- Your Highness.
- I will see the prisoner.
- The King ordered...
- The King will die soon and his son is weak.
Who do you think will rule this kingdom?
Now open this door.
Your Majesty.
Come on, filth. Up on your feet.
Stop it. Leave me.
I said leave me.
My Lady.
Sir...
I come to beg you...
to confess all and swear allegiance
to the King that he might show you mercy.
Will he show mercy to my country?
Mercy is to die quickly,
perhaps even live in the Tower.
In time, who knows what can happen?
If you can only live...
If I swear to him...
then all that I am is dead already.
You will die. It will be awful.
Every man dies.
Not every man really lives.
Drink this.
It will dull your pain.
No. It will numb my wits.
And I must have them all.
For if I'm senseless or if I wail
then Longshanks will have broken me.
I can't bear the thought of your torture.
Take it.
All right.
I have come
to beg for the life of William Wallace.
You're quite taken with him, aren't you?
I respect him.
At worst, he was a worthy enemy.
Show mercy, O thou great King,
and win the respect of your own people.
Even now
you are incapable of mercy.
And you...
To you, that word is as unfamiliar as love.
Before he lost his powers of speech
he told me his one comfort was that
he would live to know Wallace was dead.
You see?
Death comes to us all.
But before it comes to you,
know this:
Your blood dies with you.
A child who is not of your line
grows in my belly.
Your son will not sit long on the throne,
I swear it.
I'm so afraid.
Give me the strength...
to die well.
Here he comes.
Now behold the awful price of treason.
Or fall to your knees now,
declare yourself the King's loyal subject
and beg his mercy
and you shall have it.
Rope.
Raise him.
Stretch him.
That's it.
Pleasant, yes?
Rise to your knees.
Kiss the royal emblem on my cloak
and you will feel no more.
Rack him.
Enough?
It can all end...
right now.
Peace.
Bliss.
Just say it.
Cry out...
"Mercy."
Mercy.
Cry out.
Just say it. "Mercy."
- Mercy, William. Mercy.
- Jesus, man, say it.
The prisoner wishes to say a word.
Freedom!
After the beheading,
William Wallace's body was torn to pieces.
His head was set on London Bridge.
His arms and legs
sent to the four corners of Britain
as a warning.
It did not have the effect
that Longshanks planned.
And I, Robert the Bruce,
rode out to pay homage
to the armies of the English King
and accept his endorsement of my crown.
I hope you've washed your arse this morning.
It's about to be kissed by a king.
Come. Let's get it over with.
Stop.
You have bled with Wallace!
Now bleed with me.
Wallace!
In the year of our Lord 1314,
patriots of Scotland,
starving and outnumbered,
charged the fields of Bannockburn.
They fought like warrior poets.
They fought like Scotsmen
and won their freedom.