The Hovitos are near.
The poison is still fresh. Three days.
They're following us.
If they knew we were here,
they would have killed us already.
This is it.
This is where Forrestal cashed in.
- A friend of yours?
- A competitor. He was good.
- He was very, very good.
- Señor, nobody's come out alive.
Please.
Señor...
Stop. Stay out of the light.
Forrestal.
Let us hurry.
There is nothing to fear here.
That's what scares me.
- Stay here.
- If you insist, señor.
- Give me the whip.
- Throw me the idol.
No time to argue.
Throw the idol, I throw the whip.
- Give me the whip!
- Adiós, señor.
Adiós.
Dr Jones, there is nothing you can
possess which I cannot take away.
And you thought I had given up.
You chose the wrong friends.
This time it will cost you.
Too bad the Hovitos don't know you
the way I do, Belloq.
Yes, too bad. You could warn them,
if only you spoke Hovitos.
Jock! Start the engines! Get it up!
Jock, the engines!
Start the engines, Jock!
There's a big snake in the plane, Jock!
That's just my pet snake, Reggie.
I hate snakes, Jock. I hate them!
Come on,
show a little backbone, will you!
"Neo", meaning "new", and "Iithic",
I-T-H-l-C, meaning "stone".
Let's get back
to Turkdean barrow near Hazelton.
It contains a central passage
and three chambers, or cists...
Don't confuse that with robbing,
which means the removal
of the barrow's contents.
This site also demonstrates...one
of the great dangers of archaeology,
not to life and limb,
though that does happen too...
No, I'm talking about folklore.
Local tradition held that there was
a golden coffin buried at the site.
This accounts for the holes dug all over
and the poor condition of the find.
However, chamber 3 was undisturbed.
The undisturbed chamber
and the grave goods found...
...in the area give us...
...reason to date this find as we have.
Any questions, then?
No, OK. That's it for the day, then.
Don't forget Michaelson,
chapters four and five for next time.
I will be in my office on Thursday,
but not Wednesday.
I had it, Marcus. I had it in my hand.
- What happened?
- Guess.
- Belloq?
- Want to hear about it?
No. I'm sure everything
you do for the museum
conforms to the
Treaty for the Protection of Antiquities.
It's beautiful. I can get it. He can only
sell it in Marrakech. I need $2,000.
Listen, old boy,
I've brought some people to see you.
- I've got these pieces. Good pieces.
- Indiana...
The museum will buy them, as usual.
Yes, they are nice.
- Worth a ticket to Marrakech.
- The people are waiting.
- What people?
- Army lntelligence.
They knew you were coming.
They know everything.
- I don't know what they want.
- Why should I see them?
Am I in trouble?
Dr Jones, we've heard a great deal
about you.
Professor of Archaeology,
expert on the occult,
and - how does one say it? -
obtainer of rare antiquities.
That's one way of saying it.
Why don't you sit down?
Yes, you're a man of many talents.
You studied under
Professor Ravenwood in Chicago?
- Yes, I did.
- You've no idea of his whereabouts?
Just rumours really.
Somewhere in Asia, I think.
I haven't spoken to him for ten years.
We were friends, but...
...had a bit of a falling out, I'm afraid.
Dr Jones, you must understand
that this is all strictly confidential.
I understand.
Yesterday, our European sections
intercepted a German communiqué
that was sent from Cairo to Berlin.
The Nazis have teams of archaeologists
running around the world
Iooking for religious artefacts.
Hitler's a nut on the subject, crazy.
He's obsessed with the occult.
There's a German archaeological dig
going on in the desert outside Cairo.
We've got some information,
but we can't decipher it. Maybe you can.
"Tanis development proceeding.
Acquire headpiece, Staff of Ra.
"Abner Ravenwood, US."
The Nazis have discovered Tanis.
What does Tanis mean to you?
It's a possible resting place of
the Lost Ark. The Ark of the Covenant.
The chest the Hebrews
carried the Ten Commandments in.
- The Ten Commandments?
- The actual Commandments.
The tablets Moses brought down
from Mount Horeb and smashed,
if you believe in that sort of thing.
Ever go to Sunday school?
The Hebrews put the broken pieces
in the Ark. When they settled in Canaan,
- they put it in the Temple of Solomon.
- In Jerusalem.
Where it stayed for many years,
until, whoosh, it's gone.
- Where?
- Nobody knows where or when.
An Egyptian Pharaoh, Shishak,
invaded Jerusalem about 980 BC,
and may have taken
the Ark to the city of Tanis
and hidden it in a secret chamber
called the Well of Souls.
About a year after
the Pharaoh returned to Egypt,
the city of Tanis was consumed by
the desert in a year-long sandstorm.
Wiped clean by the wrath of God.
Not really. Ravenwood is the real expert.
Abner did the first serious work on Tanis.
Collected some of its relics.
It was his obsession.
But he never found the city.
Frankly, we're somewhat
suspicious of Mr Ravenwood,
being mentioned so prominently
in a secret Nazi cable.
- Rubbish. Ravenwood's no Nazi.
- Why do they want him, then?
They want the Staff of Ra headpiece
and they think Abner's got it.
What is the Staff of Ra headpiece?
The Staff is just a stick about this big,
nobody knows for sure how high.
It's capped with an elaborate headpiece
in the shape of the sun,
with a central crystal.
You'd take the Staff to a map room
with a miniature of the city on the floor.
If you put the Staff in a certain place
at a certain time,
the sun shone through here
and made a beam on the floor,
giving the location of the Well of Souls.
- Where the Ark was kept.
- Which is what the Nazis are seeking.
What does this Ark look like?
There's a picture of it right here.
That's it.
- Good God!
- That's what the Hebrews thought.
What's that coming out of there?
Lightning. Fire.
The power of God or something.
I'm beginning to understand
Hitler's interest in this.
The Bible speaks of the Ark
laying waste to entire regions.
An army which carries the Ark before it...
...is invincible.
You did it, didn't you?
- They want you to go for it.
- Oh, Marcus!
They want you to get the Ark before
the Nazis do and they'll pay handsomely.
And the museum gets the Ark
when we're finished?
- The Ark of the Covenant...
- Nothing else has come close.
It represents everything
we got into archaeology for.
Five years ago, I would've gone after it
myself. I'm rather envious.
I've got to locate Abner.
I think I know where to start.
- Suppose she'll still be with him?
- Possibly.
Marion's the least of your worries,
believe me, lndy.
What do you mean?
For nearly three thousand years,
Man has been searching for the lost Ark.
Not something to be taken lightly.
No one knows its secrets.
It's like nothing
you've ever gone after before.
Are you trying to scare me?
You sound like my mother.
We've known each other for a long time.
I don't believe in hocus-pocus.
I'm after a find of historical significance,
you're talking about the boogieman.
Besides, you know
what a cautious fellow I am.
Nice to see you again, Dr Jones.
Hello, Marion.
Indiana Jones.
Always knew someday
you'd walk back through my door.
I never doubted that.
Something made it inevitable.
What are you doing here in Nepal?
I need a piece your father collected.
I learned to hate you in the last ten years.
- I never meant to hurt you.
- I was a child in love. It was wrong.
- You knew what you were doing.
- Now I do. This is my place. Get out!
You needn't be happy about what I did,
but maybe we can help each other now.
I need one of the pieces your father
collected. Bronze piece, about this size.
- Know the one I mean?
- Yeah, I know it.
Where's Abner?
Abner's dead.
- Marion, I'm sorry.
- Do you know what you did to my life?
- I can only say sorry so many times.
- Say it again anyway.
- Sorry.
- Yeah, everybody's sorry.
Abner was sorry for taking me
to look for his junk,
I'm sorry to still be stuck in this dive.
Everybody's sorry for something.
It's a worthless bronze medallion.
Are you going to give it to me?
- I don't know where it is.
- Maybe you could find it.
3,000 bucks.
Well, that will get me back,
but not in style.
I can get you another two
in the States. It's important.
Trust me.
You know the piece I mean?
You know where it is?
- Come back tomorrow.
- Why?
Because I said so, that's why.
See you tomorrow, lndiana Jones.
- Good evening, Fräulein.
- The bar's closed.
We are not thirsty.
- What do you want?
- The same thing Dr Jones wanted.
Surely he told you there'd be
other interested parties?
It must've slipped his mind.
The man is nefarious.
I hope, for your sake,
he has not yet acquired it.
- Why? Are you willing to offer more?
- Almost certainly. Do you still have it?
No, but I know where it is.
How about a drink?
Your fire is dying here. Why don't you
tell me where the piece is right now?
Listen, Herr Mac, I don't know
who you're used to dealing with,
but nobody tells me
what to do in my place.
Let me show you what I am used to.
Take your hands off me!
Take your lousy hands off!
Wait! I can be reasonable.
- That time is past.
- You don't need that.
Wait.
I'll tell you everything.
Yes, I know you will.
Let her go.
Whisky.
Shoot them. Shoot them both.
My medallion!
At least you haven't forgotten
how to show a lady a good time.
- You're something!
- Tell you what...
Until I get back my $5,000, you're getting
more than you bargained for.
I'm your goddamn partner!
Cairo, city of the living.
A paradise on earth.
Why do you forget yourselves?
What is this?
Where did this animal come from?
Oh, no.
Cute. What an adorable creature.
Then it shall be welcome in our house.
You don't have to keep it
just because of me.
I knew the Germans would hire you,
Sallah. You're the best digger in Egypt.
My services are inconsequential to them.
They've hired every digger in Cairo.
The excavation is enormous.
They hire strong backs and pay pennies.
It's as if the Pharaohs had returned.
- When did they find the map room?
- Three days ago.
They have not one brain among them.
Except one...
He's very clever.
He's a French archaeologist.
- What's his name?
- They call him Bellosh.
Belloq. Belloq.
The Germans have
a great advantage over us.
They are near to discovering
the Well of Souls.
They're not going to find it without this.
Who can tell us about these markings?
Perhaps a man I know can help us.
Indy, there's something that troubles me.
What is it?
The Ark.
If it is there at Tanis, it is something
Man was not meant to disturb.
Death has always surrounded it.
It is not of this earth.
- Do we need the monkey?
- I'm surprised at you.
Talking that way about our baby.
- He's got your looks, too.
- And your brains.
I noticed that.
She's a smart little thing. Smart.
- Where are you going?
- She'll be all right. Have a date.
Come on, come on... Marion!
- What's this?
- It's a date. You eat them.
Why haven't you settled down
and had nine kids like Sallah?
Who says I haven't?
I do. Dad had you figured long ago.
- He said you were a bum.
- That's generous.
The most gifted bum he ever trained.
He loved you.
- Took a lot for you to alienate him.
- Just you.
Marion, get out of here! Duck!
Right!
Help! Over here, lndy!
Get out of the way! Move it!
Help me!
You can't do this to me.
I'm an American.
Indiana Jones! Help me, Jones!
Marion...
You looking for me?
- Belloq.
- Good afternoon, Dr Jones.
- I ought to kill you now.
- Not a very private place for a murder.
They don't care if we kill each other.
They're not gonna interfere
in our business.
It was not I who brought the girl into this.
Sit down before you fall down.
We can at least
behave like civilised people.
I see your taste
in friends hasn't changed.
Odd that it should end this way,
after so many stimulating encounters.
Where shall I find a new adversary
so close to my own level?
Try the local sewer.
You and I are very much alike.
Archaeology is our religion.
Yet we have both fallen
from the purer faith.
Our methods do not differ
as much as you pretend.
I'm a shadowy reflection of you. It would
take only a nudge to make you like me.
- To push you out of the light.
- Now you're getting nasty.
You know it's true. How nice.
Look at this. It's worthless.
$1 0 from a street vendor.
Bury it in the sand for a thousand years
and it becomes priceless.
Like the Ark. Men will kill for it.
Men like you and me.
What about your boss, der Führer?
I thought he was waiting
to take possession.
All in good time,
when I'm finished with it.
Jones, do you realise what the Ark is?
It's a transmitter.
It's a radio for speaking to God.
And it's within my reach.
You want to talk to God?
Let's go see him together.
I've nothing better to do.
Uncle lndy! Come back home now!
Next time, lndiana Jones,
it'll take more than children to save you.
I thought I would find you there.
Better than the US Marines, eh?
- Marion's dead.
- Yes, I know. I'm sorry.
Life goes on, lndy. There is the truth!
I have much to tell you.
First, we'll take them home.
Then I will take you to the old man.
How did Belloq do it?
Where'd he get a copy of the headpiece?
There are no pictures,
no duplicates anywhere.
I tell you only what I saw myself.
A headpiece like that one,
except the edges were rougher.
In the centre,
the Frenchman had a crystal,
and surrounding the crystal on one side
were raised markings, like that one.
They made the calculations
in the map room?
This morning.
Belloq and the boss German, Dietrich.
When they came out, they gave us a
new spot to dig in, away from the camp.
- The Well of Souls, huh?
- Come, come, look here.
- Sit down, come, sit down.
- What is it?
This is a warning
not to disturb the Ark of the Covenant.
Did Belloq get the height
of the Staff from here?
Yes, it is here. This was the old way.
This means six kadam high.
- About 72 inches.
- Wait!
And take back one kadam to honour
the Hebrew God whose Ark this is.
You said their headpiece only had
markings on one side. You sure?
Belloq's staff is too long.
They're digging in the wrong place!
I am the monarch of the sea
I am the ruler of the...
Bad dates.
I told you not to be premature
in your communiqué to Berlin.
Archaeology is not an exact science.
It does not deal in time schedules.
The Führer is not patient. He demands
constant reports and expects progress.
- You led me to believe...
- Nothing!
I only said it looked very favourable.
Besides, with the information we have,
my calculations were correct.
They're not kidding, are they?
- When does the sun hit the map room?
- About 9 in the morning.
Not much time, then.
- Where are they digging for the Well?
- On that ridge.
- But the map room is over there.
- Let's go!
Sallah?
Sallah!
What is the matter?
I'll fetch you water, I shall get it for you.
I will get you water. How is the food?
I thought you were dead.
They must've switched baskets.
- Are you hurt?
- No. Get me out of here.
They'll be back any minute.
Cut me loose, quick.
They keep asking about you.
What you know.
What's wrong? Cut me loose.
- I know where the Ark is.
- The Ark's here?
I'm coming with you. Get me out of here!
If I take you now,
they'll start looking for us.
Get me out of here! Are you crazy?
I hate to do this, but if you don't keep
quiet, this whole thing's going to be shot.
I'll be back to get you.
That's it.
Perhaps the Ark is waiting in some
antechamber for us to discover.
Perhaps there's some
vital evidence eluding us.
- Perhaps the girl can help us.
- My feeling exactly.
She kept the original for years. She may
know much if properly motivated.
I tell you the girl knows nothing.
I'm surprised you're squeamish.
That's not your reputation.
It needn't concern you.
I have just the man for the job.
Indy, here, we've hit stone.
Clear it off. Come on, find the edges.
Good, good, good. You see, lndy?
- OK, bring the pry-bars in.
- As a team, boys, as a team!
Push!
Get 'em in there. Get 'em under.
That's it. Watch your toes!
Carefully, carefully.
Sorry, lndy.
Indy, why does the floor move?
Give me your torch.
Snakes. Why did it have to be snakes?
Asps. Very dangerous.
You go first.
To escape on foot, the desert
is three weeks in every direction.
So please eat something.
I must apologise for your treatment.
No food, no water. What kind
of people are these friends of yours?
At this point in my work,
they are necessary evils.
They're not my friends.
However, with the right connections,
even in this part of the world,
we are not entirely uncivilised.
- Beautiful.
- I would very much like to see you in it.
I'll bet you would.
All right.
What have you got to drink around here?
We don't have much time.
Soon they'll harm you.
I won't be able to stop them, unless you
give me something to placate them.
Some piece of information which
I can use to protect you from them.
I've already told you everything.
I have no loyalty to Jones.
He's brought me nothing but trouble.
Marion, you are beautiful.
I don't think we need a chaperone.
Steadily... Steadily!
Down, down. Carefully, carefully.
You all right, lndy?
Gently, boys, gently, gently.
I told you it would be all right.
Sallah, get down here.
You pour.
That's good.
Whoops!
What is this stuff, René?
I grew up with this. It's my family label.
Well, I have to be going now, René.
I like you, René, very much.
Perhaps we'll meet someday
under better circumstances.
We meet again, Fräulein.
You Americans, you are all the same.
Always over-dressing
for the wrong occasions.
Now...
...what shall we talk about?
All right, take it up.
Easy!
- You're as stubborn as that girl.
- You like her too much.
Your methods of archaeology
are too primitive for me.
You would use a bulldozer
to find a china cup.
Wake your men!
- Indy, the torches are burning out.
- Go on, get out of here.
- Sallah.
- Hello, hello!
Dr Jones, whatever are you doing
in such a nasty place?
Come down, I'll show you.
Thanks, but we're very comfortable
up here. That's right, isn't it?
Yes, we are very comfortable up here.
So, once again,
what was briefly yours is now mine.
What a fitting end to your life's pursuits.
You'll be a permanent addition
to this archaeological find.
In a thousand years,
even you may be worth something.
- Son of a bitch.
- We must be going now.
Our prize is awaited in Berlin.
But I do not wish to leave you all alone.
Slimy pig, let me go. Stop it!
Hang on!
Don't fall. I've got an idea.
You traitor, get your hands off of me!
Snakes...
At your feet!
- The girl was mine!
- She's no use to the Führer's mission.
I wonder sometimes
if you have that clearly in mind.
- It was not to be, chérie.
- You bastards, I'll get you for this!
Indiana Jones, adieu.
Take this.
Wave it at anything that slithers.
This whole place is slithering!
- Indy!
- Jesus!
- Where did you get this? From him?
- I was trying to escape.
- How hard did you try?
- Where the hell were you?
- What are you doing?
- Help me, fire!
- How do we get out?
- I'm working on it.
Do it faster.
- Where are you going?
- Through that wall.
- Get ready to run, whatever happens.
- What do you mean by that?
Indy! Don't leave me here by myself.
- Here we go, get ready!
- Indy, the torch is going out!
Look, look.
They're flying it out. When it's loaded,
we'll already be on the plane.
Monsieur, let us toast our success
in the desert. To the Ark.
When we are far from here,
and not with you.
Stay with the Ark!
Look out!
- Oh, my God!
- Marion... !
I'm locked in here. I'm here!
- Indy, I'm stuck.
- Pull on the latch.
I'm stuck.
Indy, I can't force the lock.
- It's stuck.
- Turn it.
- Never mind. Get back!
Get the Ark away from here.
Put it on the truck.
We will fly it out of Cairo.
And, Gobler, I want plenty of protection.
Jones... !
Holy smoke! My friends,
I'm so pleased you're not dead.
We have no time if you want the Ark.
It's been loaded onto a truck for Cairo.
Truck? What truck?
Let's go!
Get back to Cairo.
Get us some transport to England.
Boat, plane, anything. Meet me
at Omar's. I'm going after that truck.
- How?
- I don't know. I'm making this up as I go.
Everything is arranged.
The Ark is on board.
Nothing's lacking now you're here.
- You trust these guys?
- Yes.
Mr Katanga.
Mr Katanga, these are my friends.
They are my family.
I will hear of it if they are not treated well.
My cabin is theirs.
Mr Jones, I've heard a lot about you, sir.
Your appearance
is exactly the way I imagined.
Goodbye.
Look after each other.
I am already missing you.
You're my good friend.
That is for Fayah.
That is for your children.
And this is for you.
Thank you.
A British tar is a soaring soul
As free as a mountain bird
His energetic fist
should be ready to resist
Where did you go?
- I've been cleaning up.
- Where did you get that?
- From him.
- Who "him"?
Katanga. I'm not the first woman
to travel with these pirates.
- It's lovely.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Really?
What did you say?
Wait, I don't need any help.
You do... You're not the man
I knew ten years ago.
It's not the years, honey,
it's the mileage.
I don't need a nurse. I just want to sleep.
- How's this here?
- Go away... ! Yes, it hurts.
Goddamn it, lndy. Where doesn't it hurt?
Here.
This isn't too bad.
We never seem to get a break, do we?
- What is it?
- Engines have stopped.
I'm gonna do a check.
- What's happening?
- We have most important friends.
You and the girl
must disappear in the hold. Go, go!
Don't you touch me.
- What about Jones?
- No trace yet.
Jones is dead.
I killed him. He was of no use to us.
This girl has certain value where
we're headed. She'll bring a good price.
Herr Colonel, that cargo you've taken.
Take it, but leave us the girl.
It will reduce our loss.
Savage, you are not in the position
to ask for anything.
We will take what we wish, then decide
whether to blow up your ship.
The girl goes with me.
She'll be part of my compensation.
I'm sure your führer would approve.
If she fails to please me,
you may do with her as you wish.
Excuse me.
I can't find Mr Jones.
I've looked everywhere.
He's got to be here somewhere.
- Look again.
- I've found him.
- Where?
- There.
The altar has been prepared
as you instructed.
Good. Take the Ark there immediately.
Monsieur...
I am uncomfortable
with the thought of this Jewish ritual.
Are you sure it's necessary?
Let me ask you this:
would you be more comfortable
opening the Ark in Berlin for your führer
and finding out only then
if the sacred Covenant is inside,
and whether you've
accomplished your mission
and obtained the one true Ark?
I'm going to blow up the Ark, René.
Your persistence surprises even me.
- You'll give mercenaries a bad name.
- Dr Jones...
Surely you don't think you can escape?
That depends how reasonable we're
all willing to be. All I want is the girl.
- If we refuse?
- Then your führer has no prize.
OK, stand back.
All of you, stand back, right back.
OK, Jones, you win.
Blow it up.
Yes, blow it up. Blow it back to God.
All your life has been spent
pursuing archaeological relics.
Inside the Ark are treasures
beyond your wildest aspirations.
You want to see it open as well as l.
Indiana, we are simply
passing through history.
This...this is history.
Do as you will.
Marion, don't look at it,
no matter what happens.
It's beautiful!
- Indy?
- Don't look. Keep your eyes shut!
You've done your country a great service.
We trust you found
the settlement satisfactory.
The money's fine.
The situation is unacceptable.
- I guess that wraps it up.
- Where is the Ark?
I thought we'd settled that.
The Ark is somewhere safe.
- From whom?
- It's a source of unspeakable power.
- It has to be researched.
- And it will be.
I assure you, Dr Brody. Dr Jones.
We have top men
working on it right now.
- Who?
- Top men.
Hey, what happened?
You don't look very happy.
- Fools!
- What did they say?
- They don't know what they've got.
- I know what I've got here.
Come on, I'll buy you a drink.
You know, a drink?