The word Sicario came to define the zealots of Jerusalem
assassins that hunted the Romans, invaders of their tierra
In Mexico, Sicario means Hitman
Dad
Dad,Wake up.
Allright,Allright
Come on Dad,we have to go to the soccer game
Are you going to play?
Yes
Are you sure?
Yes Dad,we have to go to the game.
Ok
Mom! Dad needs some eggs and coffee.
Hurry up,we are in a rush.
Ok,Dear
Bro...Bro.
Drop the gun.
Drop it!
A question my Friend.
Do you want to die?
I don't speak English.
You Don't speak English?
That's not good.
How is the wife?
Fine.
We had two sons
10 and 8 years old
In Juarez?
No...In Monterrey.
Better
Yes,More calm
Is good to see,you still in the fight.
I'm Sorry...For what it happened.
Take care.
In a moment you will find out what is to love God
In Yankee's Land
Attention!
All from Nogales,Group A,D,E.
Groups A,D,E.
Stay in the floor
Everybody else...
Guards load them in the busses...Now!
This group...
Whom of you had been in the United States before
Escuse me.
Where?
In Arizona.
Arizona?
Are you married?
Yes Sir
Childrens?
Yes.
Where?
In Chihuahua.
Let me see your hands.
Do you have any Tattoos?
No Sir.
Ans you,What is your Name?
Alejandro.
Alejandro what?
Alejandro Rodriguez
And where you had been?
Texas
Texas?
You where had you been?
Arizona.
Arizona?
Come to eat.
Get ready for school
Where is Dad?
He's working
When is he coming back
Don't Know.
You can't cross for "las pajaritas"
No you can't there.
But for "Los Caballeros" you can?
Yes you can do it there.
But you can't trust "Coyotes" there.
No woman can cross there.
No way!
Look,look...This is drug's Land
The only persons that cross here.
Are the "mules" and the "pollos"
And they do it to keep immigration
away from their tunnels
You never cross where they have their tunnels,Right
Do you know the area?
Let's see... For many yars this was
the best place to cross.
From here you can walk to the 86.
There's shadow and water over there.
Can you show me here the way to the tunnel.
Look,they hide the entrance behind an old car.
There!
You are making a mistake.
Don't be a fool.
Eggs
With jalapeños?
Of course.
Do you work today?
Tonight.
Do you want to play soccer in the park?
Soccer?
Yes Dad.
First get me my coffee.
Ok,we'll do
Never touch it
Understand.
Hurry up
Help me out
Give me the keys
Please calm down.
Hands up
Turn around.
What is your Name?
Silvio.
Silvio,You are going to exit 56 state road
I have a son.
From here,what you do is for your Family
Silvio,Speed up.
Now turn your lights up.
You going to stop that car
Good.
Turn on the speakers.
And tell him to come out of the car
Out of the car
Again
Get out asshole!
Ask him to open her jacket and turn around.
Open you Jacket,Turn around
Do yo know whom am I ?
Let him know that he better do it or else
I'll kill you motherfucker.
Open your Jacket.
Turn around.
Ask him to trow out his gun
You are such a good cop Silvio
Now you get out of the car.
Get out the car Silvio.
What do you want
Don't move motherfucker.
Do you know whom am I?
I'am a boss.
On the floor
Yes I know who you are.
You are the one with the lies and vinegar face
And now you will take to meet...
Your Boss
Get Up!
Get up
If you try anything,
your Daughters will die being rape by 20 men.
Turn around
Turn Around.
Get on.
I am Manuel Diaz.
I know who you are.
It's Manuel...Checked
Bon appetit
Stay still...
Otherwise he will kill us.
The kids speak English?
Then we speak English.
Eat...Eat
Eat.
Now you will find out what is to love God.