What the hell?
Goddamn son of a bitch...
- Wow.
- Hey! My turn!
Come on.
What's wrong with this picture?
Nice night for a walk.
Wash day tomorrow. Nothing clean.
Right?
Nothing clean. Right.
I think this guy's a couple cans
short of a six-pack.
Your clothes.
Give them to me. Now.
Fuck you, asshole!
Hey, sugar. How about it?
Yeah, I don't have to put up
with that bullshit, man.
She's always after me.
Hey, buddy. Did you just see
a real bright light?
See that guy?
- Hold it there!
- He's rabbiting.
Hey, hold it!
Go!
That son of a bitch...
...took my pants!
What day is it? The date!
Twelfth. May.
- Thursday.
- What year?
What?
He's got my gun. Let's go!
Guard it for me, Big Buns.
Hi. I'm late.
So am I.
- I'm in it.
- So am I.
- Honey, can I have that coffee now?
- Yes, sir.
- Who gets the burlybeef?
- I ordered barbequed beef.
- I got it without fries.
- He gets beef.
Mine's chili beef.
- Who gets the burlybeef?
- Miss?
- We're ready to order now.
- Yes, ma'am.
Oh, good heavens!
Oh, I'm so sorry!
This isn't real leather, is it?
Nice going, kid.
I ought to give you the tip.
Look at it this way:
In 100 years, who's gonna care?
The 12-gauge auto loader.
That's Italian.
You can go pump or auto.
The.45 long slide
with laser sighting.
They're brand new. Just got them in.
That's a good gun.
The beam comes on, you put the red
dot where you want the bullet to go.
You can't miss.
Anything else?
A phased plasma rifle
in the 40 watt range.
Just what you see, pal.
The Uzi nine millimeter.
You know your weapons, buddy.
Any one of these is ideal
for home defense.
So...
...which will it be?
All.
I may close early today.
There's a 15-day wait
on the handguns...
...but the rifles you can take now.
You can't do that.
Wrong.
Hi, baby.
Yeah, it's me.
I need you to come pick me up.
My bike just broke down.
I don't care! Come get me. What-!
Mort?
Hey, man. You got
a serious attitude problem.
Mort, where are you?
Come on, what are you doing?
Sarah Connor?
Yes?
I'm on my break.
Carla's got my station.
Sarah, come here! It's about you!
I mean, sort of.
It's incredible.
You won't believe this.
- Sit down. You're gonna love this!
- What?
- has been compiled
from several witnesses.
Once again, Sarah Connor, 36,
mother of two...
...shot to death
in her home this afternoon.
You're dead, honey.
- if you're into sound,
for the greatest sound around...
...come into Bob's Stereo.
We've got woofers, tweeters, and
digital audio and compact laser discs.
We've got graphic equalizers
and sound balancers that adjust-
Sorry.
Hello?
First, I'm gonna rip the buttons
off your blouse, one by one.
Then, run my tongue down your neck
to your bare, gleaming breasts.
Then, slowly...
...slowly pull yourjeans off,
inch by inch.
Ginger, it's Matt.
And lick your belly in circles,
further...
...and further down.
Then, pull your panties off...
...with my teeth.
Who is this?
Oh, God. Sarah?
Oh, Jesus. I'm sorry.
I thought you were-
Can I talk to Ginger?
Sure, Bunky.
It's the creep.
First, I'll rip the buttons
off your blouse, one by one...
- Calm down.
- You fucking pigs!
Wait till I get my hands on you!
Get off me!
Sit down, fella.
Ed!
- What do you got?
- Dead girl.
I can see that.
Sarah Ann Connors, secretary, 35,
shot six times at less than 10 feet.
- Large caliber weapon-
- You know, these work.
- What's this?
- Dead girl Two.
Sent over from the Valley division
this afternoon.
I'm sure there's a point
to all of this.
Look at the name, Ed.
"Sarah Louise...
...Connor. " Is this right?
You're kidding me.
The press will be
short-stroking it all over.
A one-day pattern killer.
I hate the weird ones.
So...
Better than mortal man deserves.
- Ginger, have you seen Pugsley?
- Not lately.
- Did you check messages?
- I thought you did.
Hi, Sarah. This is your mom.
There you are, young man.
You mind your mother.
Bye.
Hi, Sarah. Stan Morsky.
Something's come up and
I won't be able to make it tonight.
I just can't get out of it.
Sorry. I'll make it up to you.
Call you in a day or so, okay?
Sorry. Bye.
That bum.
So what if he has a Porsche.
He can't treat you like this.
It's Friday night, for chrissake!
I'll live.
I'll break his kneecaps.
Well, Pugsley still loves me.
Don't you, baby?
God... It's disgusting.
I'm gonna go to a movie.
- You and Matt have a good time.
- We will.
- You too!
- Okay.
Damn it, Matt!
Oh, shit.
Are you aware the killings occurred in
the same order as in the phone book?
What can I tell you guys?
No comment.
But lieutenant,
we've got two murders-
That coffee's two hours cold.
And I put a cigarette out in it.
- Did you reach the next girl?
- I keep getting an answering machine.
- Send a unit.
- I did.
No answer and
the manager's not home.
- Call her.
- I just called her.
Call her again.
Give me a cigarette.
Hi, there.
Fooled you.
You're talking to a machine.
But don't be shy.
Machines need love too.
So talk to it.
And Ginger, that's me...
...or Sarah will get back to you.
Wait for the beep.
Same shit.
I can hear it now. He'll be called
the goddamn "Phone Book Killer. "
I hate these press cases.
Especially the weird press cases.
Where you going?
Make a statement. Make these
jackals work for us for a change.
If I can get on the tube by 11:00...
...maybe she'll call us.
Well?
- How do I look?
- Like shit, boss.
Your mama.
This just in.
Police have announced the name
of the second murder victim...
...which took place today.
Incredibly, the names of the victims
are virtually identical.
7wo hours ago, 36-year-old
Sarah Ann Connor...
...was found dead in her apartment.
- Change this.
- Sarah Louise Connor...
Don't touch it!
...was slain earlier in her home.
Police are refusing to speculate...
...on the similarities...
...and no other connection between
them has been established as of yet.
We'll have more on this
late-breaking story as it comes in.
- You got a phone?
- It's in the back!
Four-fifty!
You've reached the LAPD
emergency number.
All our lines are busy.
If you need a police car sent out
to you, stay on the line.
2-11 in progress at Bob's Liquor,
corner of 3rd and Tavern.
Shoo! Go on!
I'm gonna make a belt out of you.
Don't make me bust you up!
Hi, there.
Fooled you.
You're talking to a machine.
But don't be shy.
Machines need love too.
So talk to it.
And Ginger, that's me...
...or Sarah, will get back to you.
Wait for the beep.
Ginger! It's Sarah! Pick up!
I'm at this place on Pico Boulevard
called TechNoir.
I'm really scared.
I think there's somebody after me.
I hope you play this back soon.
I need you to come and pick me up.
The police keep transferring me.
I'll give them another try.
The number here is 666-9176.
Call me. I need your help.
It's her.
- Sarah Connor? Lieutenant Traxler.
- Look...
...don't put me on hold
or transfer me!
- I won't. Tell me where you are.
- A bar called TechNoir.
I know it. It's on Pico.
Are you all right?
Yeah, but I think there's a guy
following me.
Listen carefully. You're in a public
place. You're safe till we get there.
But stay visible.
Don't go outside or to the restroom.
- I'll have a car there in a minute.
- Okay.
Hey, that guy didn't pay!
Come with me if you wanna live.
Come on!
This is 1-L 19.
I got a hit-and-run felony.
Suspect vehicle late-model grey Ford,
headed westbound on 7th.
He's really moving.
I'll need an ambulance
at 7th and Broadway right now.
Hold it!
All units watch
for a late-model grey Ford...
...last seen westbound
on 7th and Broadway.
Hold on.
Are you injured?
Are you shot?
Do exactly what I say!
Exactly!
Don't move unless I say.
Don't make a sound unless I say.
Do you understand?
- Do you understand?!
- Yes!
Please, don't hurt me.
I'm here to help you.
I'm Reese. Sergeant, Tech-Com.
DN 38416, assigned to protect you.
You're targeted for termination.
Intercept at National and Olympic.
Come in, 1-L 19.
This is 1-L 19. Westbound on
Olympic, approaching Overland.
This is a mistake.
- I didn't do anything.
- No, but you will.
It's very important that you live.
This isn't true. How could
that man get up after you-
It's not a man.
A machine. A Terminator.
Cyberdyne Systems model 101.
A machine?
Like a robot?
Not a robot.
A cyborg. Cybernetic organism.
No, he was bleeding.
Just a second.
Get your head down!
All right, listen.
The Terminator's an infiltration unit.
Part man, part machine.
Underneath, it's a hyper-alloy
combat chassis.
Microprocessor controlled.
Fully armored. Very tough.
But outside, it's living human tissue.
Flesh, skin, hair, blood.
Grown for the cyborgs.
- What do you want from me?
- Pay attention!
I gotta ditch this car.
The 600 series had rubber skin.
We spotted them easy.
But these are new.
They look human.
Sweat, bad breath, everything.
Very hard to spot.
I had to wait till he moved on you
before I could zero him.
Look...
...I am not stupid, you know.
They cannot make
things like that yet.
Not yet.
Not for about 40 years.
Are you saying it's from the future?
One possible future.
From your point of view.
I don't know tech stuff.
Then you're from the future too,
right?
- Right.
Cyborgs don't feel pain.
I do.
Don't do that again.
- Just let me go.
- Listen...
...and understand!
That terminator is out there.
It can't be bargained with.
It can't be reasoned with.
It doesn't feel pity or remorse...
...or fear. And it absolutely
will not stop...
...ever...
...until you are dead.
Can you stop it?
I don't know.
With these weapons, I don't know.
All units, grey Ford...
...suspect vehicle found
in a parking structure...
...at 4th and Broadway.
Location, lower level.
Suspect described as male, white,
six feet, 26 years, green overcoat.
Last seen on...
Reese?
Why me?
Why does it want me?
There was a nuclear war.
A few years from now...
...all this...
...this whole place, everything...
...it's gone.
Just gone.
There were survivors...
...here...
...there.
Nobody even knew who started it.
It was the machines, Sarah.
I don't understand.
Defense network computers.
New.
Powerful.
Hooked into everything.
Trusted to run it all.
They say it got smart.
A new order of intelligence.
It saw all people as a threat,
not just those on the other side.
It decided our fate in a microsecond.
Extermination.
Did you see this war?
No.
I grew up after.
In the ruins.
Starving.
Hiding from H-Ks.
- H-Ks?
- Hunter-Killers.
Patrol machines
built in automated factories.
Most of us were rounded up.
Put in camps for orderly disposal.
This is burned in by laser scanner.
Some of us were kept alive...
...to work...
...loading bodies.
The disposal units
ran night and day.
We were that close
to going out forever.
But there was one man...
...who taught us to fight,
to storm the wire of the camps.
To smash those metal
motherfuckers into junk.
He turned it around.
He brought us back from the brink.
His name is Connor.
John Connor.
Your son.
Your unborn son.
Drive!
Reese!
No, Reese! No!
No! They'll kill you.
You in the Cadillac!
Let me see your hands. Now.
Get out of the car!
Drop to your knees!
Out of the car.
Drop to the ground!
All units PC-907.
Suspect is in custody.
Cancel fu·her assistance.
Sarah...
...try to drink some of this.
Are you sure it's them?
I mean, maybe I should
look at the bodies.
They've been identified.
There's no doubt.
Oh, God...
Ginger!
Oh, kiddo.
Sarah...
...this is Doctor Silberman.
Hi, Sarah.
I want you to tell him
everything Reese told you.
- Do you feel up to that?
- Yeah. I guess so.
You're a doctor?
Criminal psychologist.
Is Reese crazy?
Well, that's what
we're gonna find out.
So, you're a soldier.
Fighting for whom?
With the 132nd, under Perry.
From '21 to '27.
That's the year...
...2·27p
That's right.
- Then I was assigned to Recon...
- This is great.
...under John Connor.
- Who was the enemy?
- A computer defense system built-
Damn. Sorry.
Built for SAC-NORAD
by Cyberdyne Systems.
I see.
And this...
...computer thinks it can win
by killing the mother of its enemy.
Killing him, in effect,
before he's even conceived.
Sort of retroactive abortion?
Silberman cracks me up. He had
a guy in here that burned his Afghan.
- He screwed it first-
- Shut up.
Why didn't it...
...kill Connor then? Why this
scheme with the Terminator?
It had no choice.
Their defense grid was smashed.
We'd won.
Taking out Connor then
would make no difference.
Skynet had to wipe out
his entire existence.
Is that when you captured
the lab and found- What is it?
The time displacement equipment?
That's right.
The Terminator
had already gone through.
Connor sent me to intercept,
and they blew the whole place.
How do you get back?
I can't.
Nobody goes home.
Nobody else comes through.
It's just him...
...and me.
Why didn't you bring any weapons?
Something more advanced?
Don't you have ray guns?
Ray guns.
Show me a piece
of future technology.
You go naked.
Something about the field
generated by a living organism.
- Nothing dead will go.
- Why?
- I didn't build the fucking thing!
- Okay, okay.
But this cyborg, if it's metal-
Surrounded by living tissue!
Oh, right. Right.
This is great stuff.
I could make a career out of him.
See how clever this is?
It doesn't require proof.
Most paranoid delusions are intricate,
but this is brilliant!
Why were
the other two women killed?
Most records were lost in the war.
Skynet knew almost nothing about
Connor's mother: Her full name...
...where she lived.
They just knew the city.
That Terminator
was just being systematic.
Let's go back to-
You have heard enough!
I've answered your questions,
now I have to see Sarah!
That's not up to me.
- Then why am I talking to you?
- Because-
- Who's in authority?
- Please-
Shut up!
You still don't get it, do you?
He'll find her!
That's what he does!
That's all he does!
You can't stop him!
He'll wade through you, reach down
her throat and pull her heart out!
Doc.
Let go of me!
Sorry.
So Reese is crazy?
In technical terminology...
...he's a loon.
Sarah, this is what they call
body armor.
Our TAC guys wear these.
Stop a 12-gauge round. This other
individual must've been wearing one.
Feel that. Go ahead.
What about punching
the windshield?
He was probably on PCP.
If he broke his hand,
he wouldn't feel it for hours.
- There was this guy- See this?
- Here.
Thank you.
There's a couch. Stretch out
and try to sleep.
Be an hour before your mom
gets here from Big Bear.
I can't sleep.
Try.
It may not look it, but
that couch is very comfortable.
You'll be perfectly safe.
We got 30 cops in this building.
Thank you.
- Good night.
I'm a friend of Sarah Connor.
I was told she's here.
- Could I see her?
- No, she's making a statement.
Where is she?
It may take a while.
You want to wait, there's a bench.
I'll be back.
What the hell was that?
Gunshots!
- Is it a terrorist?
- Let's go!
Stay here.
- Let's get out of here!
- Come on!
Move it, move it, move it!
I got him!
Watch him!
- Automatic weapons!
- Come on, let's go!
Fire! Fire!
Ed.
Sarah!
Reese!
This way!
KFLB news time, 4:36.
In the top story,
the largest law enforcement...
...mobilization in California
history is underway.
Police in five southern counties
are in a massive manhunt-
Take this.
All right, let's get this
off the road.
You cold?
Freezing.
Reese...
...you got a first name?
Kyle.
Kyle...
...what's it like
when you go through time?
White light.
Pain.
It's like being born, maybe.
Oh, my God!
I caught one back there.
You mean you got shot?
It's not bad.
- We gotta get you to a doctor.
- It's okay. Forget it.
What do you mean, forget it?
Are you crazy?
Take this off.
Jesus!
See, it passed right through
the meat.
This is gonna make me puke.
- Would you just talk about something?
- What?
I don't know. Anything. Just talk.
Tell me about my son.
He's about my height.
He has your eyes.
What's he like?
You trust him.
He's got a strength.
I'd die for John Connor.
At least now I know
what to name him.
Don't suppose you know
who the father is...
...so I won't tell him to get lost
when I meet him.
John never said much about him.
- I know he dies before the war-
- Wait!
I don't want to know.
So was it John that sent you here?
I volunteered.
Why?
It was a chance to meet the legend.
Sarah Connor.
Who taught her son to fight...
...organize...
...prepare, from when he was a kid.
When you were in hiding
before the war.
You're talking about things I
haven't done yet in the past tense.
It's driving me crazy!
Are you sure
you have the right person?
I'm sure.
Come on, do I look
like the mother of the future?
I mean, am I tough?
Organized?
I can't even balance my checkbook!
Look, I didn't ask for this honor
and I don't want it!
Any of it!
Your son gave me a message
to give to you.
Made me memorize it.
"Thank you for your courage
through the dark years.
I can't help you with what you face,
except to say the future is not set.
You must be stronger than
you imagine you can be.
You must survive,
or I will never exist. "
That's all.
It's a good field-dressing.
You like it?
It's my first.
Get some sleep. It'll be light soon.
Okay.
Talk to me some more.
About what?
Tell me about where you're from.
All right.
You stay down by day.
But at night you can move around.
You still have to be careful
because the H-Ks use infrared.
But they're not too bright.
John taught us ways to dust them.
That's when the infiltrators
started to appear.
The Terminators were
the newest, the worst.
It's traversing your sector
in search mode.
75· meters north of your position.
Let's go.
Reese. DN-384-
Right. Let him in.
Our spotter's got a bad paw,
so we're cutting short the patrol.
Roger, Yankee 17.
You are cleared to return.
Terminator! Terminator!
I was dreaming about dogs.
We use them to spot Terminators.
Your world is pretty terrifying.
Hey, buddy. You got a dead cat
in there, or what?
Fuck you, asshole.
Goddamn!
Thank you!
Is this enough?
Yeah, that's enough. I don't
want to ask where you got it.
- Coming.
- We need a room.
- All right.
- With a kitchen.
Have one with a kitchen?
I am dying for a shower.
We should check your bandage too.
Later. I'm going out for supplies.
Keep this.
I can't tell you where I am, Mom.
I was told not to say.
I need to know
where I can reach you.
You tell me to hide at the cabin
like a fugitive...
...and you won't tell me
what's going on?
I am worried sick, dear.
Okay.
Here's the number.
- You ready?
- Yes. Go ahead.
It's 4··-666-...
...1439.
Room nine. Got it?
- I've got it.
- I've gotta go.
I'm sorry I can't
tell you more right now.
I love you, Mom.
I love you too, sweetheart.
- Tiki Motel.
- Give me your address there.
What have we got?
Mothballs...
...corn syrup...
...ammonia.
What's for dinner?
- Plastique.
- That sounds good.
What is it?
A nitroglycerin base.
It's a bit more stable. I learned
to make it when I was a kid.
Make sure there's none
on the threads.
Like this.
Screw the end-cap on.
Very gently.
You must have had a fun childhood.
That's good.
Six more like that,
and I'll get started on the fuses.
He'll find us, won't he?
Probably.
It'll never be over, will it?
Look at me, I'm shaking.
Some legend, huh?
You must be pretty disappointed.
No...
...I'm not.
Kyle...
...the women in your time...
...what are they like?
Good fighters.
That's not what I meant.
Was there someone special?
Someone?
A girl. You know.
No.
Never.
Never?
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
So much pain.
Pain can be controlled.
You just disconnect it.
So you feel nothing?
John Connor gave me
a picture of you once.
I didn't know why at the time.
It was very old...
...torn...
...faded.
You were young, like you are now.
You seemed just...
...a little sad.
I always wondered what
you were thinking at that moment.
I memorized every line...
...every curve.
I came across time for you, Sarah.
I love you.
I always have.
I shouldn't have said that.
Think fast!
Trade places!
Faster!
Drive faster!
Kyle!
Oh, my God!
- Whoa!
- Son of a bitch!
You stay here.
Let's get out of-
Get out.
Kyle, come on. Get up.
Help me.
Come on!
Help me!
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
Faster!
Don't stop! Run!
Sarah?
Kyle!
We did it, Kyle!
We got it!
No!
Wait.
What are you doing?
Cover. So it can't track us.
Come on!
Come on.
No! Kyle!
Come on!
- Come on!
- Leave me here.
Move it, Reese!
On your feet, soldier!
On your feet!
Move it!
Back! Go back!
- Run, Sarah.
- No.
Run!
Come on, motherfucker!
No, no...
You're terminated, fucker.
Oh, Kyle...
Tape seven. November 10.
Where was I?
What's most difficult is deciding
what to tell you and what not to.
But I guess I have a while before
you're old enough to understand.
They're more for me at this point,
just so I can get it straight.
Ah, fill her up.
Should I tell you about your father?
Boy, that's a tough one.
Will it affect your decision to send
him here, knowing he is your father?
If you don't send Kyle,
you can never be.
God, a person could go crazy
thinking about this.
I suppose I will tell you.
I owe him that.
Maybe it'll help...
...if you know...
...that in the few hours
we had together...
...we loved a lifetime's worth.
What did he say?
He says, "You're very beautiful,
se·ora. "
And he's ashamed to ask you
for five dollars for this picture.
But if he doesn't,
his father will beat him.
Pretty good hustle, kid.
What did he just say?
He said there's a storm coming in.
I know.
Subs Sync Checked ..by iUropρή‎.
Έμαθα να το φτιάχνω όταν ήμουν παιδί‎.
Σιγουρέψου ότι δεν έχει
μείνει πάνω στα νήματα‎.
Έτσι‎.
Βίδωσε το πώμα‎.
Πολύ απαλά‎.
Πέρασες καλά φαίνεται
όταν ήσουν παιδί‎.
Καλό είναι‎.
Έξι ακόμη και θ' αρχίσω
με τους πυροσωλήνες‎.
Θα μας βρει‎, έτσι δεν είναι;
Πιθανόν‎.
Δεν θα τελειώσει ποτέ‎, έτσι;
Κοίτα με‎. Τρέμω‎.
Τι θρύλος που είμαι‎. Πρέπει
να έχεις απογοητευτεί‎.
Όχι‎.
Κάιλ‎, οι γυναίκες της εποχής σου‎,
πώς είναι;
Καλοί μαχητές‎.
Δεν εννοούσα αυτό‎.
Υπήρχε κάποια ξεχωριστή;
Κάποια‎.‎.‎.;
Ένα κορίτσι‎.
Όχι‎.
Ποτέ‎.
Ποτέ;
Συγνώμη‎.
Τόσος πολύς πόνος‎.
Ο πόνος μπορεί να ελεγχθεί‎.
Με το να τον αποσυνδέσεις‎.
Δεν αισθάνεσαι τίποτα;
Ο Τζον Κόνορ μου είχε δώσει
κάποτε μια φωτογραφία σου‎.
Δεν ήξερα γιατί τότε‎.
Ήταν πολύ παλιά‎,
σχισμένη‎, ξεθωριασμένη‎.
Ήσουν νέα όπως τώρα‎,
λίγο λυπημένη‎.
Αναρωτιόμουν τι σκεφτόσουν
εκείνη τη στιγμή‎.
Κράτησα στο μυαλό μου
κάθε γραμμή του προσώπου σου‎,
κάθε γωνία‎.
Γύρισα πίσω στο χρόνο για σένα‎.
Σ' αγαπώ‎. Πάντα σ' αγαπούσα‎.
Δεν έπρεπε να το πω αυτό‎.
Σκέψου γρήγορα‎.
Ν' αλλάξουμε θέσεις‎.
Πιο γρήγορα‎. Οδήγα πιο γρήγορα‎.
Κάιλ‎. Θεέ μου‎.
Μείνε εδώ‎.
Πάμε να φύγουμε‎.
Βγες έξω‎.
Κάιλ‎. Σήκω‎.
Έλα‎.
Βοήθησέ με‎. Βγες έξω‎.
Μη σταματάς‎. Τρέχα‎.
Σάρα‎.
Κάιλ‎.
Τα καταφέραμε‎. Τον σκοτώσαμε‎.
Όχι‎.
Περίμενε‎.
Τι κάνεις;
Κάλυψη για να μη μας αναχαιτίσει‎.
ΑΥΤΟΜΑΤΟΠΟΙΗΜΕΝΗ
ΑΛΛΗΛΟΥΧΙΑ ΠΑΡΑΓΩΓΗΣ
Έλα‎.
Όχι Κάιλ‎. Πάμε‎.
‎- Πάμε‎.
‎- ’σε με εδώ‎.
Κουνήσου Ρης‎. Σήκω πάνω‎,
στρατιώτη‎.
Σήκω‎. Κουνήσου‎.
Κάνε πίσω‎.
‎- Τρέξε‎, Σάρα‎.
‎- Όχι‎.
Τρέξε‎.
Τρέξε
Έλα‎, κάθαρμα‎.
Όχι‎.
Θα σ' εξολοθρεύσω‎, κάθαρμα‎.
Κάιλ‎.
Επτά‎. 10 Νοεμβρίου‎. Που ήμουν;
Το πιο δύσκολο είναι τι
πρέπει να σου πω και τι όχι‎.
Έχω καιρό μέχρι να μεγαλώσεις και
να καταλάβεις αυτές τις ηχογραφήσεις‎.
Προς το παρόν‎, είναι περισσότερο για
μένα για να ξεκαθαρίσω τα πράγματα‎.
Γέμισέ μου το‎.
Πρέπει να σου πω για τον πατέρα σου;
Με προβληματίζει αυτό πολύ‎.
Θα επηρεάσει την απόφασή σου να τον
στείλεις εδώ‎, ξέροντας ποιος είναι;
Αν δεν στείλεις τον Κάιλ‎,
δεν θα υπάρξεις ποτέ‎.
Θα μπορούσε κανείς να τρελαθεί
μελετώντας όλ αυτά‎.
Μάλλον θα σου πω‎.
Του το χρωστάω‎.
Ίσως σε βοηθήσει αν‎.‎.‎.
ξέρεις ότι οι λίγες ώρες
που περάσαμε μαζί‎,
αγαπηθήκαμε για
σε μια ολόκληρη ζωή‎.
‎- Τι είπε;
‎- Λέει ότι είσαι πολύ όμορφη‎.
Ντρέπεται να σου ζητήσει πέντε
δολάρια για τη φωτογραφία‎.
Αλλά αν δεν το κάνει‎, ο πατέρας του
θα τον σπάσει στο ξύλο‎.
Ωραίος εκβιασμός ο πιτσιρικάς‎.
Τι είπε;
Είπε ότι έρχεται καταιγίδα‎.
Το ξέρω‎.
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player