The future.
A dark, desolate world.
A world of war, suffering, loss...
on both sides.
Mutants and the humans
who dared to help them.
Fighting an enemy we cannot defeat.
Are we destined down this path?
Destined to destroy ourselves
like so many species before us?
Or can we evolve
fast enough to change ourselves?
Change our fate?
Is the future truly set?
They're here!
Time's up.
Sentinels!
Sunspot!
Let's go.
Run!
Go!
Blink! No!
Too late, assholes.
Don't move, you mutant scum!
No!
Flat on the ground,
hands behind your head!
So few of us left.
Professor?
I've found them.
Professor!
- Bobby.
- Hey, Storm.
Hey, kid.
Professor, you made it.
Whenever the Sentinels attack,
Warpath spots them...
then I send Bishop back to warn us
of the attack before it happens.
Blink scouts the next site...
and then we leave
before they ever know we were there.
Because... we never were.
What do you mean you were never there?
She projects Bishop back in time
a few days to warn the others...
of the coming attack.
So she sends Bishop back in time?
No, just his consciousness,
into his younger self.
His younger body.
Wow.
This might just work, Charles.
What might work?
The Sentinel Program was originally
conceived by Doctor Bolivar Trask.
In the early '70s, he was one of the world's
leading weapons designers.
But, covertly, he had begun
experimenting on mutants...
using their gifts
to fuel his own research.
This is extraordinary.
There was one mutant who had discovered
what he was doing.
A mutant with the ability
to transform herself into anyone.
Mystique.
I knew her as Raven.
We met when we were children,
grew up together.
She was like a sister to me.
I tried to help her...
but only succeeded in driving her away.
She hunted Trask across the world.
And at the Paris Peace Accords in 1973,
after the Vietnam War...
she found Trask...
and killed him.
It was the first time she killed.
It wasn't her last.
But killing Trask did not have
the outcome she expected.
It only persuaded the government
of the need for his program.
They captured her that day...
tortured her,
experimented on her.
In her DNA, they discovered the secrets
to her powers of transformation.
It gave them the key they needed...
to create weapons that could adapt
to any mutant power.
And in less than 50 years...
the machines that have destroyed...
so many of our kind were created.
But it all started that day in 1973...
the day she first killed.
The day she truly became...
Mystique.
You want to go back there.
If I can get to her,
stop the assassination...
keep her out of their hands...
then we can stop the Sentinels
from ever being born.
And end this war before it ever begins.
I can send someone back
a couple weeks.
Maybe a month.
But you're talking about
going back decades.
You have the most powerful brain
in the world, Professor...
but the mind can only stretch so far
before it snaps.
It would rip you apart. I'm sorry.
No one could survive that trip.
What if someone's mind
has a way of snapping back?
What if someone can heal
as fast as they're ripped apart?
It's a risk.
Yeah, I'm getting that.
Not just for you.
You do this, you change history.
That's kind of the point.
Some of us could be killed.
Some of us may never be born.
We have no idea how things may change.
We could keep going.
Keep fighting.
Until what?
You've got a decision to make.
You can keep sending Bishop back in time
over and over again to warn you,
until one day, he doesn't make it,
and you all die.
Or you can give up this life.
So that they
and everyone else who died in this war
can actually have a future.
You're asking us to sacrifice our lives
for a future we might not even be a part of.
Yes.
A second chance.
A better chance for everyone.
My people need to vote.
They just did.
They're in.
Okay, spread out.
Take your positions.
So I wake up in my younger body,
God knows where.
Then what?
You'll need to go to my house
and find me.
Convince me of all of this.
Won't you be able to just read my mind?
I didn't have my powers in 1973.
Logan, you're going to have to do for me
what I once did for you.
Lead me, guide me.
I was a very different man then.
You'll have to be patient with me.
Patience is my strongest suit.
- You'll need me as well.
- What?
After Mystique left Charles,
she came with me...
and I set her on a dangerous path.
A darker path.
It's going to take the two of us,
side by side...
at a time when we couldn't
be further apart.
Great.
So where do I find you?
Well, it's complicated.
Are you sure about this?
It's not just his power that'll be tested.
I've seen what this can do to you.
I can handle this.
Trust me.
I guess I'll see you in the next life.
Basically, your body will go to sleep
while your mind travels back in time.
As long as you're back there,
past and present will continue to coexist.
But once you wake up...
whatever you've done
will take hold and become history.
And for the rest of us,
it will be the only history that we know.
It will be like the last 50 years
never happened.
And this world, and this war...
the only person who will
remember it is you.
All right, Logan...
I need you to clear your head
and to stay as calm as possible.
What? What do you mean?
If your mind gets rocky,
it will be harder for me to hold you...
and you could start
to slip between past and future.
What if I need to get a little rocky?
Think peaceful thoughts?
Peaceful thoughts...
Do you have any good news?
Well, you don't really age,
so you'll pretty much look the same.
You won't have much time in the past.
The Sentinels will find us.
They always do.
And this time, we won't be able to run.
We'll have no escape.
This is our last chance.
- You really think this will work?
- I have faith in him.
It's not him I'm worried about, it's us.
We were young...
we didn't know any better.
We will now.
See you all soon.
This might sting a little.
Holy shit.
It worked.
What's going on?
- Gwen, get dressed.
- Who the hell are you?
I don't know what's going on.
You're supposed to be guarding
the boss's daughter, not screwing her.
Well, I didn't sleep with her.
- No?
- No.
I mean, yes, I slept with her many times.
Jimmy!
That wasn't me.
That was the old me.
I just got here 20 seconds ago.
Really? Then what happened to your clothes?
My...
Would you believe me if I told you
I was sent here from the future?
- Get out of here, sweetheart.
- Yeah.
- We're gonna take care of this comedian.
- No, you're not.
You're gonna give me the keys
to your car and some money for gas...
or you're gonna wake up in the hospital.
Trust me,
I know how these things play out.
Because you're from the future?
No.
Because of these.
What the hell?
God damn it!
Peaceful thoughts.
Jimmy! What happened to Ramon?
And why are you talking crazy talk?
- Look...
- Gwen.
Gwen, you're gonna wanna lay low
for a few days, all right? Starting now.
Come on, out.
Go.
Today, the 18th MP Brigade
is departing from Saigon,
marking the last American troops
to leave Vietnam.
and effectively ending the war.
We are reviewing
all of our defense expenditures...
and all the black books
are being opened.
We can't support a weapon
that targets our own citizens.
If these mutants, as you describe...
are already living among us...
then they are living here peacefully.
We haven't had an incident
in over 10 years.
After what happened in Cuba?
That was never confirmed.
We have very real enemies out there...
the Russians, the Chinese.
We are talking about a tenth
of a tenth...
of a tenth of our population.
Allow me to read something to you.
Please.
This was acquired by our friends
at the CIA.
It's a dissertation...
written by a mutant at Oxford University.
And I quote...
"To Homo Neanderthalensis...
his mutant cousin, Homo Sapiens..."
which is us...
"was an aberration.
The arrival of the mutated human species,
Homo Sapiens...
was followed by the immediate extinction
of their less evolved kin."
Now, we are the Neanderthal.
Speak for yourself, Dr. Trask.
You know,
when you sent our soldiers to Vietnam...
without the weapons they needed
to win the war...
you underestimated your enemy.
You do that with this enemy...
and it won't be some border skirmish
halfway around the world.
This time, the war will
be for our streets...
our cities, our homes...
and by the time
you see the need for my program...
it will be too late...
and you will have lost
two wars in one lifetime.
We are sorry, Dr. Trask...
but your Sentinel Program...
it ain't gonna fly.
Can I help you, Colonel?
Just here to give our boys
a proper send-off.
I'm sorry, sir, but we have orders.
This is a quarantined area.
Stand aside, soldier.
That's an order.
Atten-hut!
At ease.
What is all this?
Lab reports, blood tests.
It's all getting packed up
and shipped back.
Where is it going?
Same place they are.
Trask Industries.
Let's go, gentlemen.
I'm taking you out of this shit show.
Shipping home?
Not just yet.
What are you doing with those?
Something to make the ride
a little smoother.
I'm transferring you
to a private facility...
where we can run a few more tests.
Your men are not military.
Private outfit.
We're authorized to remand these men.
These troops are going home.
Well, Colonel, I don't believe
you have jurisdiction in this matter.
I'm afraid I do, son.
I'm sorry, who are you?
The question is, Major...
...who are you?
Raven!
That's not my name.
I had that.
I know.
Let's move out. Come on, let's go.
Where's Erik?
I'm on my own now.
Let's go! Move it!
Hold that plane!
Wouldn't wanna leave these boys
in this godforsaken country.
Yes, sir.
You're not coming with us, are you?
My war's not over.
The enemy is still out there.
The four privates, where did they go?
They were headed towards the tarmac.
Can I help you?
Yeah, what happened to the school?
The school's been shut for years.
Are you a parent?
I sure as hell hope not.
Who are you?
I'm Hank. Hank McCoy.
I look after the house now.
You're Beast?
Look at you.
I guess you're a late bloomer.
I don't know what you're talking about,
but I'm gonna have to ask you to leave.
So where's the Professor?
There's no professor here.
You're pretty strong for a scrawny kid.
You sure there's not
a little Beast in there?
- No, he's not here.
- Come on, Beast.
- Come on, Beastie.
- No.
I said the school's closed.
- You need to leave.
- Not until I see the Professor.
There's no professor here,
I told you that.
Look, kid.
You and I are gonna be good friends.
You just don't know it yet.
Professor!
Hank?
What's going on here?
Professor?
Please don't call me that.
Why? You know this guy?
Yeah, he looks slightly familiar.
Get off the bloody chandelier, Hank.
You can walk.
You're a perceptive one.
I thought Erik...
Which makes it slightly perplexing that
you missed our sign on the way in.
This is private property, my friend.
I'm gonna have to ask him
to ask you to leave.
I'm afraid I can't do that...
because I was sent here for you.
Tell whoever it was that sent you
that I'm busy.
That's gonna be a little tricky...
because the person who sent me was you.
What?
About 50 years from now.
I know. Stay with me.
- Like in the future, 50 years from now?
- Yeah.
- I sent you from the future?
Piss off.
If you had your powers,
you'd know I was telling the truth.
How do you know I don't have my p...
- Who are you?
- I told you.
- Are you CIA?
- No.
You've been watching me?
I know you, Charles.
We've been friends for years.
I know your powers
came when you were 9.
I know you thought you were going crazy
when it started...
all the voices in your head.
And it wasn't until you were 12...
that you realized all the voices
were in everyone else's head.
Do you want me to go on?
I never told anyone that.
Not yet, no, but, you will.
All right, you've piqued my interest.
What do you want?
We have to stop Raven.
I need your help.
We need your help.
I think I'd like to wake up now.
What does she have to do with this?
So you're saying...
they took Raven's power, and what?
They weaponized it?
Yep.
She is unique.
Yeah, she is, Hank.
In the beginning, the Sentinels
were just targeting mutants.
Then they began to identify the genetics
in non-mutants...
who would eventually have mutant children
and grandchildren.
Many of the humans tried to help us,
but it was a slaughter.
leaving only the worst of
humanity in charge.
I've been in a lot of wars.
I'd never seen anything like this.
And it all starts with her.
Let's just say for the sake of...
the sake, that I choose to believe you...
that I choose to help you.
Raven won't listen to me.
Her heart and soul
belong to someone else now.
I know.
That's why we're gonna need Magneto, too.
Erik?
- You do know where he is?
- Yeah.
Could you give me that
one more time, please?
You heard me.
He's where he belongs.
You're just gonna walk out?
Top marks.
Like I said, you are perceptive.
The Professor I know
would never turn his back...
on someone who'd lost their path.
Especially someone he loved.
You know...
I think I do remember you now.
Yeah. Tall, angry fellow
with the contentious hair.
We came to you a long time ago...
seeking your help.
And I'm gonna say to you
what you said to us then.
Fuck off.
Listen to me, you little shit.
I've come a long way,
and I've watched a lot of people die.
Good people. Friends.
If you're gonna wallow in self-pity...
and do nothing, then you're
gonna watch the same thing...
you understand?
We all have to die sometime.
Told you there was no professor here.
What the hell happened to him?
He lost everything.
Erik, Raven...
his legs.
We built the school, the labs,
this whole place...
then, just after the first semester...
the war in Vietnam got worse.
Many of the teachers...
and older students were drafted.
It broke him.
He retreated into himself.
I wanted to help, do something...
so I designed a serum to treat his spine...
derived from the same formula
that helps me control my mutation.
I take just enough
to keep myself balanced...
but he takes too much.
I tried easing him back...
but he just couldn't bear the pain,
the voices.
The treatment gives him his legs...
but it's not enough.
He's just lost too much.
You're not scared of me?
I always believed
I couldn't be the only one in the world.
Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You're hungry and alone.
Take whatever you want. We've got
lots of food. You don't have to steal.
In fact...
you never have to steal again.
And that's a promise.
I'll help you get her.
Not for any of your future shite,
but for her.
Fair enough.
But I'll tell you this.
You don't know Erik.
That man is a monster. A murderer.
You think you can convince Raven
to change? To come home?
That's splendid.
But what makes you think
you can change him?
Because you and Erik sent
me back here together.
The room they're holding him in
was built during the Second World War...
when there was a shortage of steel.
So the foundation is pure concrete
and sand. No metal.
He's being held...
a hundred floors beneath the most
heavily guarded building on the planet.
Why is he in there?
What, he forgot to mention?
JFK.
He killed...
What else explains a bullet
miraculously curving through the air?
Erik's always had a way with guns.
Are you sure you want to carry on with this?
This is your plan, not mine.
We don't have any resources
to get us in.
Or out.
It's just me and Hank.
I knew a guy.
Yeah, he'd be a young man now.
Grew up outside of D.C.
He could get into anywhere.
I just don't know
how the hell we're gonna find him.
Is Cerebro out of the question?
If only you guys had Internet.
What's "Internet?"
We have a phonebook.
I thought you'd be getting ready
for your trip, sir.
I just came to grab a couple files.
Is that a new scarf? It's nice.
Thank you.
Dr. Trask?
One second.
We added some names
to the Paris meeting.
Thank you.
Is something wrong, sir?
No. It's nothing.
Would you mind typing up my itinerary?
I don't wanna miss anything.
- Here, here, here.
- Where?
- Just stop here.
- All right, all right.
Next time I'm driving.
Don't get used to it.
What's he done now?
I will just write you a check
for whatever he took.
We just need to talk to him.
Peter! The cops are here. Again.
I'm a princess. What are you?
I'm the Wolverine.
Where's your brother?
Go upstairs and bug your sister.
But she bugs me!
What do you guys want?
I didn't do anything.
I've been here all day.
Just relax, Peter. We're not cops.
Of course you're not. If you were,
you wouldn't be driving a rental car.
How did you know we've got a rental car?
I checked your registration
when you were walking to the door.
I also had some time to kill
so I went through your rental agreement.
Saw you were from out of town.
Are you FBI?
No, you're not cops.
What's with this gifted youngsters place?
That's an old card.
- He's fascinating.
- He's a pain in the arse.
What, a teleporter?
No, he's just fast.
And when I knew him he wasn't so... young.
Young? You're just old.
So you're not afraid to show your powers?
What powers?
What are you talking about?
Do you see something strange here?
Nothing anybody would believe
if you told them.
So, who are you?
What do you want?
- We need your help, Peter.
- For what?
To break into a highly secured facility...
and to get someone out.
Prison break?
That's illegal, you know.
Only if you get caught.
So, what's in it for me?
You, you kleptomaniac,
get to break into the Pentagon.
How do I know I can trust you?
Because we're just like you.
Show him.
That's cool, but it's disgusting.
Built in 1943, the Pentagon
is the world's largest office building...
housing more than
25,000 military employees...
stretched over six million square feet.
Where's the bathroom?
He always needs to pee!
Lucky for you, you'll have...
We're getting broadcast signal down here.
What's going on?
Damn it, call Maintenance,
get them down here.
...fought for and captured the island of Iwo Jima
from the Japanese Empire.
Now, this month-long battle...
included some of the fiercest fighting
during World War II in the Pacific...
In three seconds,
those doors are going to open...
and 20 guards will be here to shoot us.
I know. That's what I'm waiting for.
What are you doing?
I'm holding your neck so you don't get whiplash.
What?
Whiplash.
Don't move!
You're good, it'll pass.
It happens with everyone.
You must have done
something pretty serious.
What did you do, man?
What did you do?
Why'd they have you in there?
For killing the President.
Wow. Shit.
The only thing I'm guilty of
is fighting for people like us.
You take karate? You know karate, man?
I don't know karate.
But I know crazy.
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and girls,
this is a Code Red situation.
We are evacuating the entire floor...
so that my associate and I...
can secure the prison.
- Who are you?
- We're special operations, CB...
FB-CID.
Perhaps you didn't hear me
when first I spoke...
but it is imperative
that you understand...
we're in a complete lockdown situation.
We have to get you to the third floor...
I'm sorry. Were you finished?
They told me you control metal.
"They"?
You know, my mom once knew a guy
who could do that.
I'm sorry, I'm just not
very good with violence.
Charles?
Good to see you too, old friend.
And walking.
No thanks to you.
You're the last person in the world
I expected to see today.
Believe me...
I wouldn't be here if I didn't have to.
If we get you out of here,
we do it my way.
No killing.
No helmet.
I couldn't disobey you even if I wanted.
I'm never getting inside of that head again.
I need your word, Erik.
Nobody move!
Hold it right there!
- Charles.
- Don't move.
Hands up, or we will shoot!
- Freeze them, Charles.
- I can't.
Hands up!
No!
Thanks, kid.
Peter, thank you very, very much.
You take care.
I saw your flight plan in the cockpit.
Why are you going to Paris?
Imagine if they were metal.
- Do me a favor and return it for me.
- Okay.
And, Peter?
Take it slow.
Where did they dig you up?
You're gonna find
this hard to believe...
but you sent me.
You and Charles.
From the future.
How did you lose them?
The treatment for my spine affects my DNA.
You sacrificed your powers
so you could walk?
I sacrificed my powers so that I could sleep.
What do you know about it?
I've lost my fair share.
Dry your eyes, Erik.
It doesn't justify what you've done.
You have no idea what I've done.
I know that you took the things
that mean the most to me.
Maybe you should have
fought harder for them.
If you want a fight, Erik...
- Sit down.
- ...I will give you a fight!
Let him come.
You abandoned me!
You took her away...
and you abandoned me!
Angel.
Azazel.
Emma.
Banshee.
Mutant brothers and sisters...
all dead!
Countless others...
experimented on.
Butchered!
Erik!
Where were you, Charles?
We were supposed to protect them!
Where were you
when your own people needed you?
Hiding! You and Hank!
Pretending to be something you're not!
Erik!
You abandoned us all.
So, you were always an asshole.
I take it we're best buddies in the future.
I spent a lot of years
trying to bring you down, bub.
How does that work out for you?
You're like me.
You're a survivor.
Do you wanna pick all that shit up?
General, maybe you should slow down,
we have a big day tomorrow.
We're celebrating, captain. It's not every day you win
a war, let alone against the American devils.
I'm getting another bottle.
Excuse me.
I'm pretty sure it was my fault.
You speak Vietnamese.
I'm an interpreter.
I speak many tongues.
Let me buy you another drink...
unless you're here with someone.
I'm alone.
A bottle of Johnnie Walker please.
You're going to the Summit tomorrow?
A pretty girl interested in politics...
Looks can be deceiving.
Lady.
Show me more, baby?
Clothes off?
What's the matter, baby?
You don't think I look pretty like this?
Fancy a game? It's been a while.
I'm not in the mood for games, thank you.
I haven't had a real sip in ten years.
I didn't kill the President.
The bullet curved, Erik.
Because I was trying to save him.
They took me out before I could.
Why would you try and save him?
Because he was one of us.
You must think me so foolish.
We've always said they
would come after us.
I never imagined they'd use
Raven's DNA to do it.
When did you last see her?
The day I left for Dallas.
And how was she?
Strong.
Driven.
Loyal.
How was she?
She was...
We were...
I could see why she meant so much to you.
You should be proud of her, Charles.
She's out there fighting for our cause.
Your cause.
The girl I raised was not capable of killing.
You didn't raise her,
you grew up with her.
She couldn't stay a little girl forever,
that's why she left.
She left because you got inside her head.
That's not my power.
She made a choice.
But now we know where
that choice leads, don't we?
She's going to murder Trask,
they're going to capture her...
and then they're going to wipe us out.
Not if we get to her first.
Not if we change history tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Charles...
for what happened.
I truly am.
It's been a while since I've played.
I'll go easy on you.
Might finally be a fair fight.
You have the first move.
The diplomats from all around the world
are arriving here today at the Hotel Royal.
It's an historic day.
It's the official ending of the United States'
military involvement in Vietnam.
There we have
the South Vietnamese Foreign Minister...
with other South Vietnamese dignitaries.
The Summit doesn't begin
for another hour.
The hotel has arranged a private room
upstairs for your special guests.
That will be plenty of time.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Hello, thank you for coming.
Congratulations on winning this war.
Now, I know you all have hands to shake
and photos to take downstairs...
so I will get right to the point.
There is a new enemy out there.
An enemy that will
render your arsenals useless...
your armies powerless...
and your nations defenseless.
You will need a new weapon for this war.
I call them Sentinels.
Named after the ancient guardians
that stood at the gates of the citadel.
They have the aeronautic capabilities
of a Harrier jet.
Armed with guns that can fire off...
more than 2,000 rounds per minute
of thermoceramic ammunition.
But size, power, speed...
you could find that at Lockheed or Boeing.
No, what makes the Sentinels
so special...
is the ability to target
the mutant X-gene.
A genetic guidance system that can
lock onto a mark a half a mile away.
It won't trigger
unless it has identified the target.
With this weapon, there will be
no human collateral damage.
If I turn it on, the system
couldn't even activate in here.
Unless there's a mutant.
There has to be a some kind of mistake.
My machines don't make mistakes.
What are you?
I assure you...
No, don't shoot it.
I assure you,
I don't know what you're talking about.
Raven!
Raven? Raven!
Raven?
Charles?
We've come for you, Erik and I.
Together.
I never thought I'd see you again.
I made you a promise a long time ago
that I would protect you.
I'm going to keep you safe.
I'm going to keep you
out of their hands.
Erik?
Erik? What are you doing?
Securing our future.
Forgive me, Mystique.
As long as you're out there,
we'll never be safe.
Erik...
Use your power, Charles. Stop him.
He can't.
He's slipping back.
I'm losing him.
Stryker!
Someone will finish
what we've started, Wolverine!
One day!
Restrain him.
Erik!
Where am I?
How the hell did I get here?
What? You came to us.
- Who are you?
- Charles.
- Charles Xavier!
- I don't know you.
What the hell is that?
Look, I can deal with this. Just go.
Stop Erik!
- Erik, please...
- I'm sorry.
Erik...
You're Logan, that's Hank McCoy,
I'm Charles Xavier.
You spent the last
couple of days with us.
You're on acid.
Somebody gave you really bad acid, yeah?
Just hold on tight,
we'll get through this together.
Oh, my God, Kitty.
She's wounded pretty bad.
I got him.
Professor?
What happened to you?
I just saw someone who's gonna
bring me a lot of pain someday.
Where's Raven?
- Gone.
- What?
We have to get out of here.
We want to know if there's
any sort of connection with...
Yesterday, the Paris Peace Summit...
was rocked by the appearance
of unidentified assailants...
the likes of which
the world has never seen.
Mass hysteria has gripped the nation
as people ask...
"Where did they come from?
Will they be back?"
And most importantly,
"Are they friend or foe?"
That was London correspondent
Toby Elliot...
reporting from the
Paris Peace Summit yesterday.
Fuck me.
What the hell are we dealing with here?
Off the record.
Two days ago, this man,
Erik Lehnsherr...
escaped from a maximum security prison
inside the Pentagon.
We believe that this woman
is a former associate of Lehnsherr's.
They were together in Cuba,
the day of the crisis in '62.
He was also implicated
in Kennedy's assassination.
What about that thing?
We don't know what that thing is, sir.
Actually, we really don't know
what any of them are.
Yes. Yes, we do.
They're mutants.
He has the power to control metal.
Last I checked, that's what
most of your weapons were made of.
And she can transform into anyone.
A general, a secret serviceman.
Even you, Mr. President.
She could walk into this office...
and order a nuclear strike
if she was in the mood.
And that's only two of them.
Do we have any countermeasures?
Any defense?
I was waiting for you
to ask me that question.
That's an experimental program, sir.
Strictly off the books.
You're telling me
these mutants are out in the world...
and our best defense
are these giant metal robots?
Many of the mutants look like us.
My Sentinels can tell the difference.
I have eight prototypes ready to go.
They're built out of a space-age polymer,
not an ounce of metal on them.
I want to make a demonstration.
I want the world to know
that we can protect them.
What do you need
to get these things operational?
I already gave that number to Congress.
Unfortunately,
they elected to shut me down.
It's going to cost a bit more
to turn them on.
- Whatever you need.
- And one more thing.
If we do manage to capture them,
I would like her.
For research purposes, of course.
I don't care who you screw,
as long as it's not me.
Terrible thing.
What is?
Being born like that.
Is it?
Can you imagine...
Looking in the mirror and seeing that
staring back at you?
Yes, I can.
Where do you think she comes from?
You think she has a family?
Yes.
She does.
If I see so much as a screw move,
I will jam this into your throat.
How did you find me?
You taught me well.
It's been a long time
since we were this close.
I missed you.
You tried to kill me.
So the rest of us could live.
What do you mean?
We received a message from the future.
Don't lie to me.
I never have, and I never will.
Humans use your blood, your genes,
to create a weapon that wipes us all out.
I was only doing what I thought
necessary to secure our future.
So what's to stop me from killing you
right now and securing my future?
Nothing.
It doesn't matter anymore.
They have your DNA.
Your blood was on the street.
Whose fault was that?
Mine.
I've seen their plans.
They're creating a weapon.
And now they have what they need
to take it further.
We have to strike now,
while we still hold the upper hand.
I've seen too many friends die, Erik.
I don't want a war.
I only want the man who murdered them.
This is war.
What happened to you?
Did you lose your way
while I was gone?
Are you still Charles' Raven?
Or are you Mystique?
Trask is the enemy.
Killing one man isn't enough.
It never was for you.
Goodbye, Erik.
What happened?
- Come on.
- Can he walk?
He needs his treatment.
- I can hear them.
- I know. It's okay.
- Can you make it stop?
- I'll get them.
Hey, hey.
Pull yourself together.
It's not over yet.
You don't believe that.
How do you know?
As these go...
this comes back.
They all come back.
Look.
I'm still here...
and she's still out there.
We need your help, Charles.
Not like this. I need you.
We can't find Raven.
Not without your powers.
I added a little extra
because you missed a dose.
Charles.
Hank, do me a favor.
Would you help me to my study, please?
Come on, I got you.
Are you sure about this?
Absolutely not.
This creature is extraordinary.
Her genes could hold the key
to mutation itself.
I need more.
That's all they were able to scrape off
the pavement in Paris.
More than blood.
I need brain tissue...
spinal fluid, bone marrow.
Imagine...
Sentinels that could transform,
adapt to any target.
If I could just get my hands on her.
This girl could leap
the program forward years...
decades into the future.
How old is your son now, Major?
Jason?
He's coming up on ten now,
if you can believe it.
Eight years from fighting age.
And how many of our sons and brothers
did we just ship home in body bags?
Maybe fifty, fifty-five thousand?
And how many more on the other side?
Never before...
in all of human history...
has there been a cause
which could unite us as a species.
Until now.
You really hate mutants, don't you?
On the contrary, I rather admire them.
The things they can do.
I see mutants as our salvation.
A common enemy.
A common struggle
against the ultimate enemy.
Extinction.
I believe our new friends...
are going to help us
usher in a new era, Bill.
A new era of genuine...
and long-lasting peace.
Attention, attention.
Transport departure in two hours.
Repeat.
When was the last time
you were down here?
The last time we went looking for students.
A lifetime ago.
Welcome, Professor.
Raven's wounded.
She won't be moving fast.
These are muscles
I haven't stretched in a long time.
Charles!
Charles? It's all right.
I'll go check the generator.
It's not the machinery, is it?
I can't do this. My mind...
Yes, you can.
- It won't take it.
- You're just a little rusty.
You don't understand.
It's not a question of being rusty.
I can flip the switches.
I can turn the knobs.
But my power comes from here.
It comes from...
And it's broken.
I feel like one of my students.
Helpless.
It was a mistake coming down here.
It was a mistake freeing Erik.
This whole thing has been
one bloody mistake.
I'm sorry, Logan,
but they sent back the wrong man.
You're right.
I am.
Actually, it was supposed to be you.
But I was the only one who could
physically make the trip.
And I don't know
how long I've got here.
But I do know that a long time ago...
actually, a long time from now...
I was your most helpless student.
And you unlocked my mind.
You showed me what I was.
You showed me what I could be.
I don't know how to do that for you.
You're right. I don't.
But I know someone who might.
Look into my mind.
You saw what I did to Cerebro.
You don't want me inside your head.
There's no damage you can do...
that hasn't already been done.
Trust me.
Come on.
Hey.
Hey, Logan.
Hi, Jean.
Kill me.
I love you.
You poor, poor man.
Look past me.
No, I don't want your suffering.
I don't want your future!
Look past my future.
Look for your future.
That's it.
Charles.
So this is what becomes of us.
Erik was right.
Humanity does this to us.
Not if we show them a better path.
You still believe?
Just because someone stumbles,
loses their way...
it doesn't mean they're lost forever.
Sometimes we all need a little help.
I'm not the man I was.
I open my mind...
and it almost overwhelms me.
You're afraid,
and Cerebro knows it.
All those voices...
so much pain.
It's not their pain you're afraid of.
It's yours, Charles.
And as frightening as it may be...
that pain will make you stronger.
If you allow yourself to feel it...
embrace it...
it will make you more powerful
than you ever imagined.
It's the greatest gift we have...
to bear their pain without breaking.
And it's born...
from the most human power.
Hope.
Please, Charles...
we need you to hope again.
Find what you were looking for?
The power's back on.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
She's lost too much blood.
She can't keep going like this.
We have no choice, Bobby.
- We can wake him up.
- No!
They need more time.
I had...
a glimpse into the past.
If we wake Logan now...
we may set our fate
on an even darker course.
They need more time.
There is someone else.
No, no one has Kitty's power.
Someone that could take her power,
take her place.
She took yours once.
Rogue.
I'm sorry, Bobby, she must be dead.
I haven't been able to make
a connection with her for years.
That's because they're keeping her
in the one place your mind can't reach
from the outside.
She's in Cerebro.
She's in your house, Professor.
They're experimenting on her.
Trying to tap into her power,
so they can take ours.
Take all of ours.
If you knew this,
why didn't you go after her?
We tried. It's too heavily guarded.
I may know a few things
about that house they don't.
Kitty, I'm going to get help.
I'm gonna bring back somebody
to help you.
Please, just bring yourself back.
Raven, stop.
Stop running.
Charles?
Where are you?
Back at the house...
where you should be.
I need you to come home.
I know what I need to do.
If you kill Trask...
you will be creating countless more
just like him.
Then I'll kill them, too.
Those are Erik's words, not yours.
The girl I grew up with
wasn't capable of killing.
She was good...
fair, full of compassion.
I have compassion.
Just not for Trask.
He's murdered too many of us.
Shut her down, Charles. Get in her head.
She's not letting me in.
I'm barely holding on.
I'm not strong enough yet.
I know what Trask has done...
but killing him
will not bring them back.
It will set you on a path...
from which there is no return.
An endless cycle of killing.
Us and them, until there is nothing left.
But we can stop it,
right now, you and I.
You just have to come home.
I have to?
You haven't changed at all, Charles.
Like I said...
I know exactly what I have to do.
You do?
Then, wherever you go, I will find you.
And, Raven, if you make me, I will stop you.
Good luck, Charles.
Where is she?
She's in an airport, boarding a plane.
She could be going anywhere.
Get some rest, Charles.
We'll track her in the morning
and find out exactly where she's going.
...rockets did land outside the base,
killing five civilians
and wounding 12 others.
Yeah?
You know
that those things can give you cancer?
I've done
some toxicology tests in the lab, and...
You want something?
Yeah, I'm...
I know it's complicated,
and there's probably all kinds of rules
and reasons for what you can and can't say,
but I was wondering if you could tell me
in the future, do I make it?
No.
Okay.
It's okay. Thanks.
Hey, kid?
It's just the world I came from.
We're going backwards in time.
Tomorrow, in front of the White House,
the President will make his announcement.
He will be joined
by Secretary of Defense Laird...
and has even sought the help
of renowned scientist Bolivar Trask...
his special advisor
to combat this mutant issue.
The White House has all three networks
to air the event live,
as it is a matter of importance
not only to the United States,
but to every citizen from around the globe.
There are no other details
about the event...
Raven...
My God.
I don't understand.
What are you doing here?
I...
I guess,
I just realized I have nowhere else to go.
- I've gotta wake Charles...
- No, don't.
Just wait.
You really shouldn't walk on this.
I've had worse.
So, you've been living here all these years?
Someone had to take care of Charles.
You know, he's missed you.
He misses who I was.
I'm not who he wants me to be anymore.
I've missed you.
So, you're like this all the time now.
Like what?
This.
No, not all the time.
I take a shot in the morning,
and I need another if I get worked up.
- Worked up?
- Yeah, yeah, when I'm...
...emotional or excited.
Any animal urges.
Usually, I can fight them off.
Well, maybe, we shouldn't have to fight off
the things that come naturally to us.
Do you remember one of the last things
you said to me?
That I would never be deemed beautiful,
looking like this?
Do you still think that?
Maybe. You saw what happened in Paris.
You know what they think of us.
What do you think?
I think you're beautiful.
What about yourself?
You should get some rest.
I'm glad you're home.
Hank?
Do you remember
the last thing I said to you?
It was, "Mutant and proud."
The old gas and water pipes
lead straight to the house.
The walls are made of reinforced steel.
In other words, a door.
You're walking directly over the hall now.
I've been on that slab.
Let me show you how it feels.
Rogue, Rogue, come on. Wake up.
Rogue.
Come on, Rogue, wake up.
Wake up, it's me.
No.
Rogue, Rogue, Rogue, it's okay.
He's with me.
We're gonna get you out of here.
Erik, Bobby.
Get out of there! Now!
Take her!
Bobby! No!
Bobby!
Professor!
Get us out of here.
- Bobby.
- I know.
I'm sorry, Charles.
Where's Bobby?
I'm sorry, Kitty.
Hello, Logan.
Rogue.
Raven was here.
- I screwed up.
- Shit.
We can't track her now.
She's cut her ties.
Hey, I saw in the news last night
there's going to be an announcement
in Washington this afternoon
about a new protocol for mutants.
I set the system I designed...
to record any news about Paris
over all three networks...
and PBS.
All three? Wow.
Yeah, and PBS.
Look what I found.
Tomorrow, in front of the White House,
the President will make his announcement.
He will be joined
by Secretary of Defense Laird...
and has even sought the help
of renowned scientist Bolivar Trask...
his special advisor
to combat this mutant issue.
The White House has asked...
Raven doesn't realize...
that if she kills Trask
at an event like that...
with the whole world watching...
Then I came a long way for nothing.
And there's more bad news.
I saw in a report...
they found traces of her blood in Paris.
For all we know,
they already have her DNA...
which is all they'd need.
To create the Sentinels of the future.
There's a theory in quantum physics...
that time is immutable.
It's like a river.
You can throw a pebble into it...
and create a ripple, but the current
always corrects itself.
No matter what you do, the river
just keeps flowing in the same direction.
What are you trying to say?
What I'm saying is...
what if the war is inevitable?
What if she's meant to kill Trask?
What if this is just simply who she is?
Just because someone stumbles,
loses their way...
doesn't mean they're lost forever.
No, I don't believe that theory, Hank.
And I cannot believe
that is who she is.
Ready the plane.
We're going to Washington.
You all right?
Getting there.
Whatever happens today,
I need you to promise me something.
You've looked into my mind
and seen a lot of bad...
but you've seen the good, too.
The X-Men.
Promise me you'll find us.
Use your power, bring us together.
Guide us. Lead us.
Storm. Scott.
Jean.
Remember those names.
There are so many of us.
We will need you, Professor.
I'll do my best.
Your best is enough.
Trust me.
There's 12 carriers inbound, 10 miles!
They've found us.
Thousands of people
will be gathered here today.
They've come from all over the world...
to witness history,
along with news crews...
from at least 50 different countries.
Thank you.
Can I see your invitations, please?
Yes, you may.
These two are with me.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
Logan!
Please, this way, sir.
Fourth infantry...
Took a Bouncing Betty.
What happened to you?
Friendly fire.
The worst kind.
Yeah.
I haven't found her yet,
but she has to be here.
The President of the United States.
My fellow Americans...
today we face the gravest threat
in our history...
mutants.
We have prepared for this threat.
In the immortal words
of Robert Oppenheimer...
"Behold.
The world will never be the same again."
Can I help you?
No, you can't.
Here they come.
This is for you, brothers and sisters.
Raven?
I have her.
Let me go, Charles.
There. You see?
Secret Serviceman.
Left of the stage.
- Got him.
- Go.
What the hell are you doing?
I didn't tell you to activate them.
I didn't.
Raven, please, listen to me.
We've been given a second chance
to define who we are.
Don't do this.
Gentlemen, you cannot pass this point.
We can't stop that many.
No, but we can slow them down.
Erik!
Storm!
Go, go, go!
Take us to DEFCON 3.
Mr. President, we are Code Red.
What's our air defense readiness?
All our air defenses are ready one.
What the hell happened out there?
I will fix it.
You said that before.
I wanted to make a statement.
Now the whole goddamn world
knows we can't protect them.
I will fix it.
You damn well better.
Charles!
Is everybody okay?
No!
Behind you.
Do what you were made for.
Where are you?
I got this! Go!
Oh, dear God, no.
So much for being a survivor.
One of them is in here.
No, no, no! Don't kill it!
I need it alive.
What the hell has happened?
You built these weapons to destroy us.
Why?
Because you are afraid of our gifts.
Because we are different.
Humanity has always feared
that which is different.
Well, I am here to tell you...
to tell the world...
you are right to fear us.
We are the future.
We are the ones
who will inherit this earth.
And anyone who stands in our way...
will suffer the same fate
as these men...
you see before you.
Today was meant to be a display
of your power.
Instead I give you a glimpse...
of the devastation my race
can unleash upon yours.
Let this be a warning to the world.
And to my mutant
brothers and sisters out there...
I say this.
No more hiding.
No more suffering.
You have lived in the shadows...
in shame and fear for too long.
Come out.
Join me.
Fight together in a brotherhood of our kind.
A new tomorrow...
that starts today.
All those years wasted...
fighting each other, Charles.
To have a precious few of them back...
- Mr. President, sir.
- Stand down.
I said, stand down!
You want to make a statement?
Kill me. Fine.
But spare everyone else.
Very heroic, Mr. President...
but you had no intention...
of sparing any of us.
The future of our species begins now.
You used to be a better shot.
Trust me, I still am.
Get out of my head, Charles!
Raven.
Please, do not make us the enemy today.
Look around you.
We already are.
Not all of us.
All you've done so far...
is save the lives of these men.
You can show them a better path.
Shut her down, Charles.
I've been trying to control you
ever since the day we met...
and look where that's got us.
Everything that happens now...
is in your hands.
I have faith in you, Raven.
He's all yours, Charles.
If you let them have me,
I'm as good as dead.
You know that.
I know.
Goodbye, old friend.
Goodbye, Erik.
Are you sure you should let them go?
Yes.
I have hope for them.
There's going to be a time, Hank,
when we are all together.
What about Logan?
Buckminster Fuller is a
great example of an architect...
whose ideas were very similar
to those of a utopian future.
Good morning, Logan. Late start.
Have a good lunch.
Good job.
Very good job.
Storm.
Jean.
Hey, Logan.
Are you okay?
You're here.
Where else would I be?
Whoa.
Easy, pal.
Well, some things never change.
It's good to see you, Scott.
Uh-huh.
See you later, Jean.
Professor.
Logan, is everything all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think it is.
You did it.
Did what?
Logan, don't you have a class to teach?
A class to teach?
History.
History?
Actually, I could use some help with that.
Help with what?
Pretty much everything after 1973.
I think the history I know
is a little different.
Welcome back.
It's good to see you, Charles.
It's good to see everyone.
Well...
I had a promise to keep.
You and I have
a lot of catching up to do.
Yeah.
What's the last thing you remember?
Drowning.
The past.
A new...
and uncertain world.
A world of endless possibilities.
And infinite outcomes.
You kidding me?
He's alive!
Countless choices define our fate.
Each choice, each moment...
a ripple in the river of time.
What do you want us to do with him,
Major Stryker?
Enough ripples...
and you change the tide.
I'll take him from here.
For the future is never truly set.